<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><language>zh-cn</language><title>经济学人 . 中文网</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org</link><item><title>Drizzle and drought 久旱难逢及时雨</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82998</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_563164">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 悠悠万事97 于 2012-9-23 15:38 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
【导读】由于西班牙橄榄受干旱影响减产，高档食用油——橄榄油的价格飙升；假以时日，或许其他橄榄油生产国能对占统治地位的西班牙造成冲击？正是：<br />
<br />
炎炎九日下瑶池，<br />
萧瑟秋风落泪时。<br />
遥看大洋缥缈处，<br />
春风拂煦和平枝，<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong><font color="Red">Olive-oil prices 橄榄油的价格</font></strong><br />
<br />
<strong><font color="Black">Drizzle and drought 久旱难逢及时雨，小打小闹能翻天？</font></strong><br />
<br />
<font color="SlateGray">The soaring cost of dressing a salad连色拉油都快要用不起了！</font><br />
<br />
Sep 22nd 2012 | from the print edition <br />
•&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <br />
•&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
 Treasure groves 珍宝园林<br />
<br />
ANCIENT artifacts unearthed by archaeologists show that olive oil has been an integral part of Mediterranean life for thousands of years. Appetite for the stuff has since spread: supermarket shelves in northern Europe and other rich countries bow under the weight of an array of oils. The Mediterranean, with its baking summers and warm, wet winters, usually provides an ideal climate for olive groves. But a drought in Spain is having a dramatic impact on the market, according to Thomas Mielke of Oil World, a research firm.<br />
考古学家发掘出来的古代艺术品告诉我们，几千年来，橄榄油就是地中海沿岸人民生活不可或缺的一部分。随着悠悠岁月，对这种食品的爱好四处传播：北欧国家与其他发达国家的超级市场货架上充斥着各色橄榄油品。地中海国家夏季炎热，冬季温暖湿润，通常有着让橄榄园林大行其道的理想气候。但供职于研究公司“食油世界”的托马斯•米尔柯（Thomas Mielke of Oil World）声称，西班牙的干旱对市场造成了戏剧化的冲击。<br />
<br />
Spain is the Saudi Arabia of olive oil, accounting for nearly half of global production. The absence of rain in Spain might reduce total global output by around 20% compared with a year ago, when the world was awash in over 3m tonnes of olive oil.<br />
正如沙特阿拉伯在石油领域的<font color="Blue">地位</font>一样，西班牙持橄榄油生产领域之牛耳，产量几达全球之半。去年全世界的橄榄油产量高达300多万吨，但由于西班牙干旱缺雨，今年的产量或许会比去年缩水20%。<br />
<br />
High levels of production then had pushed prices to a nine-year low. But over the past three months the price of extra virgin olive oil, the best-quality stuff, has risen by over 50%, to about $3,400 a tonne. Stocks left over from last year’s bumper harvest are helping to keep price rises in check but prices over $4,000 a tonne are in prospect. And in some respects last year’s overproduction is compounding the problem of the drought. Record yields left olive trees weakened by the strain and unable to bear as much fruit this year.<br />
去年由于产品数量庞大，橄榄油价曾被压到了9年来的最低点；但在过去3个月里，质量最高的特级初榨橄榄油价格上涨已超过50%，达到每吨大约3400美元的水平。尽管去年丰收而囤积下来的货物现在压制了价格的上扬，但每吨售价突破4000美元大关将为期不远。去年的过量产出在某种程度上与干旱有共同作用，因为创纪录的产量让橄榄树因受到的压力过大而虚弱不堪，今年无法结出同样多的果实。<br />
<br />
High prices are a welcome boost to other parts of southern Europe. Italy and Greece are the next-largest producers, responsible for another 20% of global output. But the surge in prices may also help some parts of the world not usually associated with olive groves.<br />
南欧其他国家欢迎橄榄油价格高企这一令人振奋的好消息。意大利和希腊的产量占全球总产量的20%，是仅次于西班牙的橄榄油生产大国。价格的高峰可能也会让一些世界上不大栽种橄榄的地方得益。<br />
<br />
Europe’s big producers have long since looked beyond home markets, where consumption has peaked. Northern Europe, whose holidaymakers have become accustomed to the flavours of the south, are consuming more olive oil. Germans are drizzling five times more and the British nearly ten times more olive oil over their food than in 1990. America is the world’s third-largest market, with demand growing by almost 6% a year for two decades, according to Rabobank.<br />
欧洲橄榄油生产大国的国内消费市场已经饱和，它们早就盯紧了国外市场。北欧国家人民在度假时已经适应了南欧的口味，这些国家现在的橄榄油消费增加了。德国人虽说消费量不大，但已是1990年的5倍，而英国人的消费量则几乎是那时的10倍。据荷兰协作银行（Rabobank）统计，美国的消费量在20年间几乎每年递增6%，现在其市场居世界第三。<br />
<br />
The bank sniffs an opportunity for California’s olive growers. Higher prices for imports, the chance that the EU will cut subsidies and long-running concerns over the quality of imports (“extra virgin” is a loose category) all stand to improve the competitiveness of costlier Californian oil. American olive oil might grab as much as 5% of the domestic market by 2017, says Rabobank. High-quality oil imported from newcomers such as Australia and Chile also stands to gain.<br />
该银行察觉到这是加州橄榄种植者的良机。进口价格高涨、欧盟可能将要削减补贴以及长期以来对进口橄榄油质量的担心（特级初榨只是一个大略范畴），这些因素都能让价格更高的加州橄榄油更富竞争力。荷协银行认为，美国橄榄油或许能在2017年攫取多达5%的国内市场份额。从澳大利亚与智利等新兴生产国进口的高质量橄榄油的地位也会增强。<br />
<br />
Spanish olive-oil exporters are unconcerned. Australian presses squeeze out just 20,000 tonnes a year and California’s merely 7,000 tonnes, compared with 1m tonnes from Spain. Maybe they should fret more. Europe’s winemakers, also dominant since antiquity, ignored the early signs of the rise of New World vintners.<br />
西班牙橄榄油出口商对此不置一顾。澳大利亚年产量仅2万吨，加州更是只有区区7000吨，而西班牙的产量则高达100万吨。或许他们应该多关注一点才是。从古代起就占据统治地位的欧洲葡萄酒厂商就曾对美洲葡萄酒酿造者崛起的早期迹象漠然视之。<br />
<br />
</td></tr></table>
<div class="attach_nopermission">
<div>
<h3>本帖子中包含更多资源</h3>
<p>您需要 <a href="member.php?mod=logging&amp;action=login" onclick="showWindow('login', this.href);return false;">登录</a> 才可以下载或查看，没有帐号？<a href="member.php?mod=register" title="注册帐号">立即注册</a> 

<a href="http://www.ecocn.org/connect.php?mod=login&op=init&referer=forum.php%3Fmod%3Dviewthread%26tid%3D82998&statfrom=login" target="_top" rel="nofollow"><img src="static/image/common/qq_login.gif" class="vm" /></a>

</p>
</div>
</div>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82998</guid></item><item><title>Brideshead revisited 耶稣: 故园风雨后</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82973</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_562990">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 悠悠万事97 于 2012-9-23 15:54 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
【导读】据《圣经》四福音书记载，耶稣本是单身汉，从未结过婚；但据最近发现的古文物记载，他曾说过“我的妻子”这样的话……历史真相究竟如何？有《七绝•耶稣》一首叹曰：<br />
<br />
风霜雨雪两千年，<br />
扑朔迷离不晓天。<br />
疑昔救主神归日，<br />
谁倚阑干望碧苑？<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong><font color="Red">Jesus 耶稣</font></strong><br />
<br />
<strong><font color="Black">Brideshead revisited 故园风雨后</font></strong> [注1]<br />
<br />
<font color="SlateGray">The greatest story ever told (revised and updated)史无前例的最伟大故事（经改正与更新）</font><br />
<br />
Sep 22nd 2012 | from the print edition <br />
•&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <br />
•&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
 Cherchez la femme 神秘莫测，原因不明[注2]<br />
<br />
THE Gnostics of the early Christian era prized esoteric knowledge as a means of spiritual fulfilment. They would have enjoyed the furore about a newly-discovered scrap of one of their holy texts which seems to quote Jesus speaking of “my wife”. Karen King of Harvard University presented a translation at a conference in Rome on September 18th.<br />
基督教早期诺斯替教派[注3]推崇神秘知识为精神满足的手段。如果看到了新近发现的一件他们的神圣文本残片，他们一定会很欣赏它引起的狂热：残片上似乎引用了耶稣所说的“我的妻子”这样的话。9月18日，哈佛大学的卡伦•金（Karen King of Harvard University）在罗马的一次会议上提交了这一残片的翻译件。<br />
<br />
Churches that believe their priests must be celibate in order to be like Jesus are not about to change their rules, though. Assuming the fragment is genuine, it shows only that others talked about Jesus using that word. The definition of “wife” is open to question too: Gnostic writing also features terms such as “bridal chamber”, used without any connotation of sexual intimacy.<br />
有些教堂认为，<font color="Blue">只有神甫独身方能奉耶稣为楷模，</font>但在此事发生后它们也并不打算很快改变规矩。即便这一残片确系真迹，这也只能表明其他人在谈到耶稣时使用了这样的字眼。就连“妻子”的定义在此也不无争议：诺斯替教派的著作中也会有像“洞房”这一类的特色<font color="Blue">用词</font>，但其中并不带有任何性亲密的<font color="Blue">含义</font>。<br />
<br />
Nor is it unusual for other ancient texts to differ from the Bible’s four “canonical” gospels. The Gnostic “Gospel of Philip” for example—part of a collection discovered in a jar in Egypt in 1945—refers to Jesus’s relationship with his mother, her sister and a “companion” Mary Magdalene, whom, it says, he loved more than the other disciples, and used to kiss (whether amorously, in friendship or in respect is unclear). It seems to date from the same time as the new text.<br />
其他古文物内容与圣经的正统四福音书 [注4] 所述有异也并非不寻常之事。例如，诺斯替教派的《腓力福音》[注5] 是1945年在埃及的一个罐子里发现的一套文物的一部分，其中谈及耶稣与他的母亲、妹妹和一个“同伴”——抹大拉的马利亚——的关系。该福音书声称，耶稣爱抹大拉的马利亚，甚于爱他的其他门徒，还时常亲吻她（但并未提及<font color="Blue">亲吻</font>是出于肉欲或友情或尊重）。这部福音书的年代似乎与以上新文本残片相同。<br />
<br />
Far from fearing such discoveries (“Da Vinci Code”-style), churches applaud them. Controversies that spark interest in who Jesus really was may also make people think about what he really said.<br />
教堂竟然全然不惧这类“达芬奇密码”式的发现，反而对之鼓掌欢迎。如果争论能激起人们对耶稣到底是怎样一个人的兴趣，它也就可能会让人们去<font color="Blue">深</font>思他真正说过<font color="Blue">的事情</font>。<br />
<br />
<br />
[注1] Brideshead Revisited（中文或译《故园风雨后》）是英国BBC27年前的电视连续剧，影响深远；许多观众认为可以归入一流电视节目之列。<br />
[注2] Cherchez la femme，法语，原意为“找出那个女人”； 对某男子举止异常又难以解释原因，即可用这一表达来形容。<br />
[注3] Gnostics：诺斯替，是早期基督教的一派。<br />
[注4] 四福音书是《新约圣经》的前四部，分别为《马太福音》、《马可福音》、《路加福音》与《约翰福音》。<br />
[注5] Gospel of Philip：《腓力福音》，教会将之列为伪经，认为它是诺斯替教派的伪作；《腓力福音》中描述了耶稣与抹大拉的马利亚间的亲密关系。<br />
<br />
</td></tr></table>
<div class="attach_nopermission">
<div>
<h3>本帖子中包含更多资源</h3>
<p>您需要 <a href="member.php?mod=logging&amp;action=login" onclick="showWindow('login', this.href);return false;">登录</a> 才可以下载或查看，没有帐号？<a href="member.php?mod=register" title="注册帐号">立即注册</a> 

<a href="http://www.ecocn.org/connect.php?mod=login&op=init&referer=forum.php%3Fmod%3Dviewthread%26tid%3D82973&statfrom=login" target="_top" rel="nofollow"><img src="static/image/common/qq_login.gif" class="vm" /></a>

</p>
</div>
</div>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82973</guid></item><item><title>China and Japan 岛屿争端波澜再起，战争疑云笼罩亚洲</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82954</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_562829">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 敛刃 于 2012-9-23 13:57 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
【导读】为了亚洲和世界的利益，或许和平解决钓鱼岛争端是最好的出路<br />
<br />
<strong><font size="2"><font color="Red">China and Japan<br />
中日关系</font></font></strong><br />
<br />
<font size="4"><strong>Could Asia really go to war over these?<br />
亚洲<font color="Blue">各国</font>真的会因岛屿争端而开战吗？</strong></font><br />
<br />
<strong>The bickering over islands is a serious threat to the region’s peace and prosperity<br />
钓鱼岛之争给亚洲地区的繁荣与稳定带来了严重的威胁</strong><br />
<br />
<font color="Silver">Sep 22nd 2012 | from the print edition</font><br />
<br />
<span id="mp3_Pvi"></span><script type="text/javascript" reload="1">$('mp3_Pvi').innerHTML=AC_FL_RunContent('FlashVars', 'soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecocn.org%2Fforum.php%3Fmod%3Dattachment%26aid%3DNDg4MTh8ZGE1YmM3YmViNTgwODBjYzg5OTFiNDg4NDYzNWNjZmZ8MTM0ODQxNDc1NA%253D%253D%26request%3Dyes%26_f%3D.mp3', 'width', '290', 'height', '24', 'allowNetworking', 'internal', 'allowScriptAccess', 'never', 'src', 'static/image/common/player.swf', 'quality', 'high', 'bgcolor', '#FFFFFF', 'menu', 'false', 'wmode', 'transparent', 'allowscriptaccess', 'none', 'allowNetworking', 'internal');</script><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
THE countries of Asia do not exactly see the world in a grain of sand, but they have identified grave threats to the national interest in the tiny outcrops and shoals scattered off their coasts. The summer has seen a succession of maritime disputes involving China, Japan, South Korea, Vietnam, Taiwan and the Philippines. This week there were more anti-Japanese riots in cities across China because of a dispute over a group of uninhabited islands known to the Japanese as the Senkakus and to the Chinese as the Diaoyus. Toyota and Honda closed down their factories. Amid heated rhetoric on both sides, one Chinese newspaper has helpfully suggested skipping the pointless diplomacy and moving straight to the main course by serving up Japan with an atom bomb.<br />
<br />
确切地说，亚洲各国并不是“从一粒沙里看世界”的【注1】，但在海岸附近那些零散的小型海礁和浅滩上，它们却发现自己的国家利益受到了重大威胁。今<font color="Blue">年</font>夏天发生了一系列海洋领土纠纷，中国、日本、韩国、越南、台湾和菲律宾都被卷入其中。本周，由于一片无人居住的群岛引发的争端（日方称为尖阁诸岛，中方称为钓鱼岛），<font color="Blue">中国各地</font>又掀起了一波反日浪潮。日本丰田汽车公司和本田汽车公司被迫关闭了在中国的工厂。中日双方言辞激烈，而其中有一家中国报纸“热心地”提出了建议：跳过毫无意义的外交行为，直接上“主菜”——给日本来一颗原子弹。<br />
<br />
That, thank goodness, is grotesque hyperbole: the government in Beijing is belatedly trying to play down the dispute, aware of the economic interests in keeping the peace. Which all sounds very rational, until you consider history—especially the parallel between China’s rise and that of imperial Germany over a century ago. Back then nobody in Europe had an economic interest in conflict; but Germany felt that the world was too slow to accommodate its growing power, and crude, irrational passions like nationalism took hold. China is re-emerging after what it sees as 150 years of humiliation, surrounded by anxious neighbours, many of them allied to America. In that context, disputes about clumps of rock could become as significant as the assassination of an archduke.<br />
<br />
幸好，这不过是荒谬的夸张说法罢了。中国政府明白维护和平可以带来经济利益，<font color="Blue">事后</font>试图淡化岛屿争端。如果不去考虑历史上的情况——特别是中国崛起和一百多年前德意志帝国崛起之间的相似之处，可以认为中国政府的这种行为完全是非常理性的。当年，欧洲没有任何一个国家能在冲突中获得经济利益。但德国认为全世界发展得太慢，跟不上自己日益强大的国力，于是像民族主义那样原始蛮横的<font color="Blue">狂热情绪</font>占了上风。中国把刚过去的150年视为屈辱史，如今重新崛起；而它周边的邻国焦虑不安（其中有很多都是美国的盟友）。在这种环境下，岛屿争端可能像某位大公遇刺那样具有重大意义【注2】。<br />
<br />
<strong>One mountain, two tigers<br />
一山二虎</strong><br />
<br />
Optimists point out that the latest scuffle is mainly a piece of political theatre—the product of elections in Japan and a leadership transition in China. The Senkakus row has boiled over now because the Japanese government is buying some of the islands from a private Japanese owner. The aim was to keep them out of the mischievous hands of Tokyo’s China-bashing governor, who wanted to buy them himself. China, though, was affronted. It strengthened its own claim and repeatedly sent patrol boats to encroach on Japanese waters. That bolstered the leadership’s image, just before Xi Jinping takes over.<br />
<br />
乐观人士指出，最近的冲突主要是一出政治戏剧——是日本选举和中国领导层换届的产物。日本政府即将从某个私人日本“岛主”手中购买几座岛屿，因此尖阁诸岛纠纷进一步升温了。日本政府的目的在于避免东京都知事染指这些岛屿——这位爱抨击中国的都知事曾经想要以个人名义购岛【注3】。 然而，中国的主权受到了侵犯。中方强调自己对钓鱼岛的所有权，并反复派遣巡逻船进入日方水域。在习近平即将继任之前，此举提升了领导层的形象。<br />
<br />
More generally, argue the optimists, Asia is too busy making money to have time for making war. China is now Japan’s biggest trading partner. Chinese tourists flock to Tokyo to snap up bags and designer dresses on display in the shop windows on Omotesando. China is not interested in territorial expansion. Anyway, the Chinese government has enough problems at home: why would it look for trouble abroad?<br />
<br />
乐观人士称，从更<font color="Blue">一般</font>的角度来说，亚洲正忙于发展经济，没有多少时间去挑起战争。中国目前是日本最大的贸易伙伴。中国游客蜂拥来到东京，在表参道大街抢购手提包和名牌服装【注4】。中国没有兴趣去进行领土扩张；而且中国政府应对国内问题已经左支右绌了，为什么还要在国际上自找麻烦呢？<br />
<br />
Asia does indeed have reasons to keep relations good, and this latest squabble will probably die down, just as others have in the past. But each time an island row flares up, attitudes harden and trust erodes. Two years ago, when Japan arrested the skipper of a Chinese fishing boat for ramming a vessel just off the islands, it detected retaliation when China blocked the sale of rare earths essential to Japanese industry.<br />
<br />
实际上，亚洲各国确实有理由保持睦邻友好，而最近的这次争端可能也会像以前的一些纠纷那样渐渐平息。但每当岛屿之争爆发时，各国的态度就趋于强硬，而彼此间的信任也渐渐消磨殆尽。两年前，<font color="Blue">一艘</font>中方渔船在钓鱼岛附近和日方船只相撞，日本因此逮捕了中方船长。其后日本尝到了中国的反击：中方对日方进行了稀土禁售，而稀土对日本工业来说必不可少。<br />
<br />
Growing nationalism in Asia, especially China, aggravates the threat (see <a href="http://www.economist.com/node/21563301" target="_blank">article</a>). Whatever the legality of Japan’s claim to the islands, its roots lie in brutal empire-building. The media of all countries play on prejudice that has often been inculcated in schools. Having helped create nationalism and exploited it when it suited them, China’s leaders now face vitriolic criticism if they do not fight their country’s corner. A recent poll suggested that just over half of China’s citizens thought the next few years would see a “military dispute” with Japan.<br />
<br />
在亚洲地区——特别是在中国，民族主义愈演愈烈，加重了领土争端的威胁（见<a href="http://www.economist.com/node/21563301" target="_blank">另文</a>）。不管日本对钓鱼岛的“所有权”是基于何种法理，其根源都在于野蛮的疆土扩张行为。各国媒体都在利用学校教育中常常灌输的一种民族偏见。中国领导人促进了民族主义的形成并且在适当的时候加以利用；如今倘若他们不维护本国的立场，就会<font color="Blue">面对尖刻的批评</font>。最近的一次民意测验显示，略微过半数的中国公民认为在接下来的几年内中日之间会发生“军事冲突”。<br />
<br />
The islands matter, therefore, less because of fishing, oil or gas than as counters in the high-stakes game for Asia’s future. Every incident, however small, risks setting a precedent. Japan, Vietnam and the Philippines fear that if they make concessions, China will sense weakness and prepare the next demand. China fears that if it fails to press its case, America and others will conclude that they are free to scheme against it.<br />
<br />
因此，这些岛屿事关重大——与其说是由于渔业资源、石油和天然气，不如说它们成了一种高赌注政治游戏的筹码，而这种政治游戏将决定亚洲的未来。每一次摩擦，不管是多么的微不足道，都有可能为将来埋下伏笔。日本、越南和菲律宾担心如果它们做出让步，中国将查觉到它们的软弱，并准备提出其他要求。中国则担心如果自己未能据理力争，美国和别国会认为可以随意在中国背后策划阴谋。<br />
<br />
<strong>Co-operation and deterrence<br />
合作与威慑</strong><br />
<br />
Asia’s inability to deal with the islands raises doubts about how it would cope with a genuine crisis, on the Korean peninsula, say, or across the Strait of Taiwan. China’s growing taste for throwing its weight around feeds deep-seated insecurities about the way it will behave as a dominant power. And the tendency for the slightest tiff to escalate into a full-blown row presents problems for America, which both aims to reassure China that it welcomes its rise, and also uses the threat of military force to guarantee that the Pacific is worthy of the name.<br />
<br />
亚洲引起了世界的怀疑：该地区处理岛屿争端尚且不力，又将如何应对真正的危机呢？比如朝鲜半岛问题？比如台海问题？中国不断尝试以国力相欺，让世界各国那种根深蒂固的不安感更加强烈——中国倘若成为主导性强国，又会如何行事？而美国一方面要向中国保证欢迎其崛起，另一方面又要用军力威胁来确保“太平洋”名副其实，目前亚洲这种小题大做的趋势也给美国带来了难题。<br />
<br />
Some of the solutions will take a generation. Asian politicians have to start defanging the nationalist serpents they have nursed; honest textbooks would help a lot. For decades to come, China’s rise will be the main focus of American foreign policy. Barack Obama’s “pivot” towards Asia is a useful start in showing America’s commitment to its allies. But China needs reassuring that, rather than seeking to contain it as Britain did 19th-century Germany, America wants a responsible China to realise its potential as a world power. A crudely political WTO complaint will add to Chinese worries (see <a href="http://www.economist.com/node/21563310" target="_blank">article</a>).<br />
<br />
有些解决方案将花上一代人的时间。亚洲的政治家圈养了一条条民族主义毒蛇，现在他们不得不开始拔去这些毒蛇的尖牙；忠于史实的教科书将起到很大的作用。在接下来的几十年里，美国的外交政策将主要针对中国的崛起。奥巴马将“轴心”转向亚洲是一个很好的开始，向各盟国表明了美国的决心。但中国<font color="Blue">需要得到美国的保证</font>——美国是想让负责任的中国来发挥作为世界强国的潜力，而不会试图向英国在19世纪钳制德国那样钳制中国。而美国那份具有政治攻击性的 WTO 申诉将让中国更为担忧（见<a href="http://www.economist.com/node/21563310" target="_blank">另文</a>）【注5】。<br />
<br />
Given the tensions over the islands (and Asia’s irreconcilable versions of history), three immediate safeguards are needed. One is to limit the scope for mishaps to escalate into crises. A collision at sea would be less awkward if a code of conduct set out how vessels should behave and what to do after an accident. Governments would find it easier to work together in emergencies if they routinely worked together in regional bodies. Yet, Asia’s many talking shops lack clout because no country has been ready to cede authority to them.<br />
<br />
鉴于岛屿争端的紧张局势（亚洲各国对历史的记载也是互相矛盾），需要立刻采取三项保护措施。其一是限制冲突事件的规模，避免争端演化成危机。如果能制定一系列行为准则，来阐明船只应当如何运作、以及发生意外时如何处理，海洋上的冲突就不会这么<font color="Blue">棘手</font>了。如果各国政府按例行程序在地区机构中展开合作，在紧急情况下合作起来就会更加容易。然而，亚洲很多的地区论坛都只是缺乏影响力的“清谈俱乐部”，因为没有任何国家愿意把权力割让给这些组织。<br />
<br />
A second safeguard is to rediscover ways to shelve disputes over sovereignty, without prejudice. The incoming President Xi should look at the success of his predecessor, Hu Jintao, who put the “Taiwan issue” to one side. With the Senkakus (which Taiwan also claims), both Mao Zedong and Deng Xiaoping were happy to leave sovereignty to a later generation to decide. That makes even more sense if the islands’ resources are worth something: even state-owned companies would hesitate to put their oil platforms at risk of a military strike. Once sovereignty claims have been shelved, countries can start to share out the resources—or better still, declare the islands and their waters a marine nature reserve.<br />
<br />
第二项保护措施就是不带偏见地再次搁置主权争端。胡锦涛把“台海问题”暂时放在一边，即将上台的习近平应当学习他这位前任的成功之处。在尖阁诸岛的问题上（台湾也声称拥有其“主权”），毛泽东和邓小平都愿意把主权问题交由下一代来决定。如果岛屿资源也不可小视的话，这么做就更说得通了——倘若搭建石油平台有受到军事打击的风险，即使是国有公司也会三思而后行。一旦各国搁置了主权之争，就可以开始共同开发资源——或许在更好的情况下，可以<font color="Blue">宣布</font>这片岛屿和周边水域为海洋自然保护区。<br />
<br />
But not everything can be solved by co-operation, and so the third safeguard is to bolster deterrence. With the Senkakus, America has been unambiguous: although it takes no position on sovereignty, they are administered by Japan and hence fall under its protection. This has enhanced stability, because America will use its diplomatic prestige to stop the dispute escalating and China knows it cannot invade. Mr Obama’s commitment to other Asian islands, however, is unclear.<br />
<br />
但并非所有问题都能通过合作得到解决；因此第三项保护措施就是加强威慑力。在尖阁诸岛问题上，美国的态度一直很明确：尽管它在主权方面不选边、不站队，但由于诸岛是由日本管理，因此也就受到美方的保护。这样也就巩固了稳定局面，因为美国将运用其外交威信来避免岛屿争端升级，而中国也清楚<font color="Blue">自己无法</font>采取武装入侵。然而，奥巴马并未对亚洲其他岛屿做出明确保证。<br />
<br />
The role of China is even more central. Its leaders insist that its growing power represents no threat to its neighbours. They also claim to understand history. A century ago in Europe, years of peace and globalisation tempted leaders into thinking that they could afford to play with nationalist fires without the risk of conflagration. After this summer, Mr Xi and his neighbours need to grasp how much damage the islands are in fact causing. Asia needs to escape from a descent into corrosive mistrust. What better way for China to show that it is sincere about its peaceful rise than to take the lead?<br />
<br />
而中国扮演的角色更为重要。中国领导人坚称本国日益壮大的国力不会对邻国造成威胁。他们还称自己会以史为鉴。在一百年前的欧洲，<font color="Blue">数年</font>的世界和平与全球化发展让各国领导人受到了诱惑，认为自己可以冒民族主义之险，而不会引火烧身。在今年夏天之后，习近平和中国邻国的领导人需要认识到岛屿争端实际上将带来多少危害。猜忌和疑虑正在慢慢侵蚀亚洲，亚洲需要从这个深渊里爬上来。而中国如果想要证明自己有和平崛起的诚意，带头行动起来就是最好的办法。<br />
<br />
<font color="Silver">from the print edition | Leaders</font><br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>译者注：<br />
</strong><br />
时事背景：<a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E9%87%A3%E9%AD%9A%E5%8F%B0%E5%88%97%E5%B6%BC%E4%B8%BB%E6%AC%8A%E5%95%8F%E9%A1%8C" target="_blank">钓鱼岛及其附属岛屿主权问题</a>。<br />
<br />
1. see the world in a grain of sand 是援引英国诗人威廉·布莱克的诗：<br /><div class="quote"><blockquote>To see a world in a grain of sand<br />
And a heaven in a wild flower<br />
Hold infinity in the palm of your hand<br />
And eternity in an hour</blockquote></div><div class="quote"><blockquote>一沙见世界<br />
一花窥天堂<br />
手心握无限<br />
须臾纳永恒<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;——译者不详</blockquote></div><br />
2. the assassination of an archduke 此处是指<a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E8%90%A8%E6%8B%89%E7%83%AD%E7%AA%9D%E4%BA%8B%E4%BB%B6" target="_blank">萨拉热窝弗朗茨·斐迪南大公遇刺事件</a>：1914年6月28日为塞尔维亚的国庆日，在巴尔干半岛的波士尼亚，奥匈帝国皇位继承人<a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E6%96%90%E8%BF%AA%E5%8D%97%E5%A4%A7%E5%85%AC" target="_blank">斐迪南大公</a>（Archduke Franz Ferdinand）夫妇被塞尔维亚族青年普林西普（一名隶属塞尔维亚的恐怖组织“黑手社”的波斯尼亚学生）枪杀。这次事件使7月奥匈帝国向塞尔维亚宣战，成为了<a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E6%AC%A1%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C%E5%A4%A7%E6%88%98" target="_blank">第一次世界大战</a>的导火索。<br />
<br />
3. 此人为现任日本东京都知事<a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E7%9F%B3%E5%8E%9F%E6%85%8E%E5%A4%AA%E9%83%8E" target="_blank">石原慎太郎</a>，作风强硬、高调。相关言行可参见链接。<br />
<br />
4. <a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E8%A1%A8%E5%8F%82%E9%81%93" target="_blank">表参道</a>在东京，为日本著名外国品牌时装店林立之地。<br />
<br />
5. <a href="http://www.ftchinese.com/story/001046602" target="_blank">美国即将在 WTO 对中国提起新申诉</a>，此为 FT 中文网的报道。<br />
<br />
</td></tr></table>
<div class="attach_nopermission">
<div>
<h3>本帖子中包含更多资源</h3>
<p>您需要 <a href="member.php?mod=logging&amp;action=login" onclick="showWindow('login', this.href);return false;">登录</a> 才可以下载或查看，没有帐号？<a href="member.php?mod=register" title="注册帐号">立即注册</a> 

<a href="http://www.ecocn.org/connect.php?mod=login&op=init&referer=forum.php%3Fmod%3Dviewthread%26tid%3D82954&statfrom=login" target="_top" rel="nofollow"><img src="static/image/common/qq_login.gif" class="vm" /></a>

</p>
</div>
</div>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82954</guid></item><item><title>Pornography and patriotism 色情电影和爱国主义</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82936</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_562756">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 盛夏浅 于 2012-9-23 13:19 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
【<font color="DarkOrange">导读</font>】：提到岛国动作片，我们会激动；提到钓鱼岛，我们也会激动。我们......该激动再激动吧！<br />
<br />
<font color="Red"><strong><font color="Red">Pornography and patriotism<br />
色情电影和爱国主义</font></strong></font><br />
<br />
<font size="4"><strong>Can’t we all just get it on?<br />
我们所有人能不激动吗？</strong></font><br />
<br />
A Japanese actress reminds her Chinese fans how conflicted they are<br />
一名日本女星让她的中国粉丝注意到了他们是多么的矛盾<br />
<br />
<font size="2"><font color="Silver"><i>Sep 22nd 2012 | BEIJING | from the print edition </i></font></font><br />
 <br />
<img id="aimg_uUFYK" onclick="zoom(this, this.src, 0, 0, 0)" class="zoom" width="290" height="435" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20120922_CNP002_0.jpg" border="0" alt="" /><br />
Sora Aoi belongs to the world<br />
苍井空是世界的<br />
<br />
<font size="3">OF ALL the positions with which Sora Aoi has excited her Chinese fans (and there have been many), this was among the more surprising. As anti-Japanese sentiment flared across China, the former porn star issued an online appeal, in fetching calligraphy, for Sino-Japanese friendship. One placard waved at anti-Japanese protests over the disputed Senkaku/Diaoyu islands read simply: “the Diaoyu islands belong to China; Sora Aoi belongs to the world.”<br />
<br />
在苍井空让中国千万粉丝兴奋的所有<font color="Blue">体位</font>中，这次的“<font color="Blue">体位</font>”算是出奇地怪。随着中国国内反日情绪高涨，昔日的色情明星苍井空在网上大秀精湛书法，呼吁“中日友好”。在由钓鱼岛（尖阁列岛）争端引发的反日游行中，有游行者挥舞着一条简洁的标语：钓鱼岛是中国的；苍井空是世界的。<br />
<br />
This odd slogan underlines the mixed and often contradictory feelings Chinese people can have about Japan. Brought up to hate it for its historic crimes, they also admire it for being better at some things than China: electronic goods; social order; comic books—and pornographic videos. Ms Aoi, unlike her government, has done nothing to hurt the feelings of the Chinese people, or at least the young men among them. She has more than 13m followers on Sina Weibo, a Chinese microblog, and her public appearances have caused near-riots with a rare pro-Japanese slant.<br />
<br />
这条奇葩标语表明了中国人民对日本时常矛盾的复杂情绪。<font color="Blue">由于日本在历史上犯下种种罪行，中国教育人民仇日。</font>但中国人民也因日本在一些方面强于中国而表示赞赏，比如电子产品、社会秩序和漫画书，还有色情电影。<font color="Blue">苍女士</font>与日本政府不同，未曾伤害过中国人民的感情，或者至少说，没有伤害过中国男性青年的感情。新浪微博上关注她的人数已经超过了1300万。<font color="Blue">她的公开亮相曾引起发几近暴动般的狂热支持，这样带有亲日色彩的骚动在中国可不多见。<br />
</font><br />
Hers was not the only cause that hitched its wagon to the demonstrations. Some took part for the chance of letting off steam without feeling the sharp end of the police’s anger. Some waved portraits of Chairman Mao, who in fact was rather insouciant about these inalienable specks of Chinese sovereignty. Most stayed away altogether. Han Han, a writer, racing driver and one of China’s most popular bloggers, called for looters and vandals to be punished.<br />
<br />
<font color="Blue">苍井空并非唯一借这次反日游行大肆炒作的人。</font><font color="Blue">有些人参与游行，只为了借机享受一下在不受警察干涉情况下泄愤的滋味。</font>有人高举毛主席肖像，<font color="Blue">而实际上肖像上这个人对中国主权不可分割的钓鱼岛却漠不关心。</font>还有大部分群众完全不参与游行。中国作家、赛车手、最受欢迎的博主韩寒发出呼吁，应该对趁机抢劫者和故意破坏他人财产者进行处罚。<br />
<br />
Ms Aoi’s appeal received some sympathetic comments among the 150,000 or so that it attracted. But many of her fans, like the nation as a whole, were fully behind the protests. Some taunted her with obscene insults and threats.<font color="Red"> One comment, translated by ChinaSMACK, a website, sought to make the best of things, suggesting that, </font>when it takes back the Diaoyu islands, China should capture Ms Aoi alive.<br />
<br />
苍井空在微博发出呼吁后，众多网友对此进行评论，评论条数约达15万，其中少数对她的呼吁表示支持。大部分粉丝，与全中国人民一样，都完全支持反日抗议游行。还有人回复下流言论对她进行辱骂和恐吓。<font color="Blue">由ChinaSMACK网站翻译的一条评论设想了最美好的情况：[</font>color=Blue]拿下钓鱼岛，活捉苍井空</font>。</font></td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82936</guid></item><item><title>A bigger bang更为振聋发聩</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82835</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_562050">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 悠悠万事97 于 2012-9-19 20:05 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
【导读】说起来，炸药这玩意要整好也挺不容易，一要爆炸威力大，二要安全、不至于一碰就炸，而这二者又往往不可兼得；因此到现在，广泛使用的炸药还都是七老八十的古董货，而当年搞出TNT的诺贝尔名声如此显赫自然不足为奇。不过老牌军火大国在这方面不愧人才辈出：君不见，密西根大学有人发现，用共结晶法混合两种炸药，可令其威力一如既往，使用起来也不那么危险，这样便免去了“杀人三千，自损八百”之厄。有道是：<br />
<br />
雾里硝烟民主图，<br />
文功武卫功夫足。<br />
毕格棒响震聋聩，<br />
却把新桃换旧符。<br />
<br />
<strong><font color="Red">Explosives 炸药</font></strong><br />
<br />
<strong><font color="Black">A bigger bang更为振聋发聩</font></strong><br />
<br />
<font color="SlateGray">A new hybrid explosive is safer to handle but still powerful一种新的混合炸药，其使用更安全，但威力犹在</font><br />
<br />
Sep 15th 2012 | from the print edition <br />
•&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <br />
•&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <br />
MODERN warfare involves plenty of new technology, from pilotless drones to powerful computer networks and satellite sensors. But the explosives which are used in battle were invented a long time ago. The two most commonly deployed belong to a class of organic chemicals called nitramines. One, RDX, is also widely used in industrial applications like mining and demolishing buildings. Its use as an explosive began in the 1920s. HMX, a related compound and one of the most powerful explosives, dates back to the second world war. Both are sometimes used with trinitrotoluene, a different type of compound more commonly known as TNT. It is over 100 years old. <br />
包括无人机、强大的计算机网络和卫星传感器在内的大量新技术正在现代战争中应用，但战争中使用的炸药却是很久以前就发明了的。最常用的两种炸药都属于硝胺类（nitramine）有机化合物。其中之一是RDX [注1]，20世纪20年代开始成为军用炸药，但也广泛应用于工业采矿与拆房等。另一种是二次大战时开始应用的HMX [注2]；它与RDX的化学结构类似，是威力最大的炸药之一。这两种炸药有时都与一种与它们结构不同的炸药三硝基甲苯（trinitrotoluene,俗称TNT [注3]）混用，而TNT的历史超过百年。<br />
<br />
A good explosive needs to be extremely powerful but not too sensitive to avoid its being detonated accidentally, such as by dropping it. These can be conflicting properties. As Alex Contini of the Centre for Defence Chemistry at Cranfield University in Britain points out, explosives developed in recent years are either too sensitive or too expensive for large-scale use.<br />
优良炸药必须威力极大，但也不能过于敏感，以免在掉到地上这类意外发生时爆炸。这两种性质常常是互不相容的。正如英国克兰菲尔德大学国防化学中心（Centre for Defence Chemistry at Cranfield University）的亚历克斯•康蒂尼（Alex Contini）指出的那样，近年开发的炸药不是过份敏感就是价格太高，<font color="Blue">无法大规模使用</font>。<br />
<br />
One such explosive is CL-20. This was developed by the American navy as a rocket propellant, a substance which involves the sudden release of energy by rapid oxidisation, in effect a controlled explosion. CL-20 is more powerful than RDX and HMX, but its higher sensitivity means that it also explodes more easily.<br />
美国海军作为火箭推进剂开发的CL-20[注4] 就是一种这样的炸药。它可以通过迅速氧化突然释放能量，而这种氧化其实是一种可控爆炸。CL-20比RDX和HMX的威力更大，但也更为敏感，因此更容易发生爆炸。<br />
<br />
The most common way to desensitise an explosive is by mixing it with a non-explosive material, such as wax or paper. Although that works, it also reduces the amount of bang you get. What if the desensitising material is itself an explosive of lower sensitivity? The problem is that the resulting material is as sensitive as its most sensitive component.<br />
让炸药减敏的最常用方法是把它与石蜡或纸张等非爆炸物混合。虽然这种方法可行，但这也降低了爆炸力。是否可以用本身也是炸药但却不那么敏感的物质来减敏呢？这样做的问题在于，由此生成的混合炸药的敏感性与各成分中敏感性最高的那种相同。<br />
<br />
Adam Matzger of the University of Michigan and his colleagues have discovered a way around that problem by using a process called co-crystallisation, which is commonly used by drugmakers to modify the physical properties of a pharmaceutical. They report in Crystal Growth &amp; Design that by mixing CL-20 in such a way they have been able to lower its sensitivity but retain most of its explosive power.<br />
共结晶是药品制造者用来改变药物物理性质的一种方法；密西根大学（University of Michigan）的亚当•玛兹戈尔（Adam Matzger）等人发现，用这种方法可以避开炸药的威力与低敏不相容问题。他们在《晶体生长与设计》（Crystal Growth &amp; Desigh）杂志上撰文报告说，他们能通过共结晶将CL-20与其它物质混合而减敏，同时又保留其绝大部分威力。<br />
<br />
At the heart of the process is the formation of crystals, an ability endowed to some materials by nature. Crystals are the result of molecules arranging themselves in a regular pattern extending in all three dimensions. Sometimes two crystalline materials that do not react with each other can be mixed to form a so-called co-crystal. To do that they are both dissolved in a common solvent, then left alone to crystallise together. Because the arrangement of molecules within the co-crystal is very different from the original crystal, it modifies the physical properties of the material—in this case CL-20’s sensitivity.<br />
这一过程的核心是结晶的形成。如果某种物质的分子以<font color="Blue">规则模式</font>向所有三维延展排列便形成结晶，但只有部分物质受到大自然眷顾，能够形成结晶。有时人们可将两种相互不反应的结晶物混合在一起，令其形成所谓共晶；为此需要将它们一起溶解在一种公共溶剂中，然后置放形成结晶。由于共晶中分子的排列方式与原来晶体大不相同，这就改变了物质的物理性质；这次他们改变的是CL-20的敏感性。 <br />
<br />
Dr Matzger made a co-crystal consisting of two parts of CL-20 and one part HMX. The hybrid explosive has nearly the same explosive power as CL-20 but the lower sensitivity of HMX. Because the process of crystallisation can be scaled up relatively easily, Dr Matzger, whose work was funded by America’s Defence Threat Reduction Agency, thinks this new explosive could make a bigger bang soon.<br />
玛兹戈尔博士制作了一种由两份CL-20和一份HMX组成的共晶。混合炸药的威力几乎与CL-20相当，但敏感性接近不那么敏感的HMX。这是一个美国降低国防威胁局（America’s Defence Threat Reduction Agency）的资助项目；玛兹戈尔博士认为，扩大生产这种共结晶的过程相对简单，因此新炸药可能很快就会投入广泛应用。<br />
<br />
<br />
[注1] RDX ：黑索今，或译海扫更，是英文Hexogeon的译称，化学名环三亚甲基三硝胺，缩写RDX ，一种军用高能炸药。<br />
<br />
[注2] HMX, 即 octogen, 中文译名奥克托今，即环四亚甲基四硝胺。<br />
<br />
[注3] TNT应为2，4，6-trinitrotoluene，即2，4，6-三硝基甲苯。<br />
<br />
[注4] CL-20，即2,4,6,8,10,12-hexanitro-2,4,6,8,10,12-hexaazaisowurtzitane 或 HNIW，中文名六硝基六氮杂异伍兹烷。<br />
<br />
附宋代诗人王安石《元日》诗： <br />
　　爆竹声中一岁除，春风送暖入屠苏。 <br />
　　千门万户曈曈日，总把新桃换旧符。<br />
</td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82835</guid></item><item><title>Pondering the past 追思大英帝国历史</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82787</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_561573">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 敛刃 于 2012-9-18 16:49 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
【导读】大英帝国本身无所谓好坏善恶；对帝国的审视首先要植根于它所处的历史时期之中<br />
<br />
<font size="2"><strong><font color="Red">The British empire<br />
大英帝国</font></strong></font><br />
<br />
<strong><font size="4">Pondering the past<br />
追思历史</font></strong><br />
<br />
<strong>Britain’s empire was far more complex than its critics appreciate<br />
英帝国比批评家们所认为的要复杂许多</strong><br />
<br />
<font color="Silver">Sep 15th 2012 | from the print edition</font><br />
<br />
<span id="mp3_9At"></span><script type="text/javascript" reload="1">$('mp3_9At').innerHTML=AC_FL_RunContent('FlashVars', 'soundFile=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecocn.org%2Fforum.php%3Fmod%3Dattachment%26aid%3DNDg2NzJ8NzA4ZWI4ZWY5ZGY5ZjliNDBmNWU2MzUzZGI1MDhjMGV8MTM0ODQxNDc0OQ%253D%253D%26request%3Dyes%26_f%3D.mp3', 'width', '290', 'height', '24', 'allowNetworking', 'internal', 'allowScriptAccess', 'never', 'src', 'static/image/common/player.swf', 'quality', 'high', 'bgcolor', '#FFFFFF', 'menu', 'false', 'wmode', 'transparent', 'allowscriptaccess', 'none', 'allowNetworking', 'internal');</script><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>Unfinished Empire: The Global Expansion of Britain.</strong> By John Darwin. <i>Allen Lane; 478 pages; £25. To be published in America in February by Bloomsbury; $35. </i>Buy from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1620400375/theeconomists-20%20" target="_blank">Amazon.com</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1846140889/theeconomists-20%20" target="_blank">Amazon.co.uk</a><br />
<br />
<strong>《未竟的帝国：英国的全球扩张》</strong>，约翰•达尔文著。<i>艾伦莱恩出版社出版，全书478页，售价25英镑。美国地区将由布鲁姆斯伯里出版社于明年二月出版，售价35美元。</i><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1620400375/theeconomists-20%20" target="_blank">Amazon.com</a>、<a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1846140889/theeconomists-20%20" target="_blank">Amazon.co.uk</a> 有售。<br />
<br />
JOHN DARWIN has spent his whole career thinking about<i> Pax Britannica</i>. Three years after his magisterial study, “The Empire Project: The Rise and Fall of the British World-System, 1830-1970”, the Oxford historian has returned yet again to the subject. This time, though, his focus is different and the period he covers is longer. His new book is not a straightforward narrative of the British empire’s rise and fall. Rather, it is a brilliantly perceptive analysis of the forces and ideas that drove the creation of an extraordinary enterprise. At its zenith the British empire was almost impossibly grand in conception and yet was frequently so “improvised and provisional in character” as to appear almost ramshackle.<br />
<br />
约翰•达尔文的毕生精力都用于研究“不列颠治世”【注1、2】。三年前，这位牛津大学的历史学家曾发表过权威著作《帝国伟业：<font color="Blue">1830年到1970年间</font>英国世界体系的兴衰》，如今他又重新回到了这个课题上。然而这一次他的研究重点有所不同，所涉及的历史时期也更长一些。达尔文的新书并未对大英帝国的兴衰展开平铺直叙。确切地说，这本书对推动一项伟业开创的种种动力和理念进行了极富洞察力的分析。在大英帝国的鼎盛时期，人们认为它宏伟壮观得几乎不可思议，但它在实际上却常常只是“昙花一现、命不久长”，以至于看起来似乎即将瓦解崩塌。<br />
<br />
In fact, argues Mr Darwin, there was, at least for its first 100 years or so, no single vision of empire, but several. These reflected the unusually pluralistic and intellectually open society that Britain had become during the “long” 18th century (from 1688 to 1815). It was, above all, at this stage an empire driven less by the state than by the personal ambitions of people with vastly different backgrounds and agendas: from fortune-seeking gentry to merchants looking for new markets, impoverished economic migrants and evangelical missionaries.<br />
<br />
达尔文称，至少在大英帝国最初的100年左右，人们对帝国的愿景实际上并不统一，而是存在好几种。这些愿景表明英国在“漫长的”19世纪（从1688年到1815年）变成了极为多元化、思想开放的社会。毕竟，在这个阶段，帝国发展与其说是在由国家推动，不如说是个人雄心的作用。这些人出身背景大不相同，社会角色也是迥异：有些是追求财富的上流社会人士，有些是寻找新市场的商人；有些是一贫如洗的经济移民，有些是福音派传教士。<br />
<br />
Over time the state began, often reluctantly, to take on more of the protection and ultimately the running of these inchoate ventures overseas. Before that, the colonising of America and the gradual takeover of India by the East India Company were chiefly commercial projects that were dependent on private capital and private risk. And the American settler uprising that began in 1775 was essentially a reflection of the tensions between this private-enterprise notion of empire and the growing financial burden of securing it both from rival European colonial powers and from displaced indigenous peoples.<br />
<br />
随着时间的流逝，带着几分不情愿，英国开始更多地去负责保护这些不成熟的海外产业，最终对它们展开了运作。在此之前，对美洲的殖民、以及用东印度公司逐步接管印度【注3】，都主要是一些取决于私人资本和私人风险的商业项目。英帝国既要防备与其竞争的其他欧洲殖民强国，又要防备背井离乡的本土民族，<font color="Blue">因此</font>财政负担不断加大；而始于1775年的美洲移民起义在本质上反映了帝国的这种私营企业观念和财政负担之间的紧张关系。<br />
<br />
If there was no single vision of empire, neither was the project ever monolithic in practice. Between the late 18th and the early 19th centuries four very different types of British empire had begun to emerge. The first were the self-governing colonies in North America, the Caribbean and Australasia; second, India and the opportunity it provided for Britain to project power from the Persian Gulf to the South China Sea; and third, a ragbag of smaller territories, some of them bases acquired as way stations to India, some trade entrepots such as Hong Kong and Singapore and some “maritime bridgeheads” in east and west Africa with relatively ungoverned hinterlands. The fourth kind of empire, suggests Mr Darwin, was a more informal one in places such as Argentina and Egypt where British influence was exercised through commerce, investment and shrewd diplomacy (occasionally of the gunboat kind).<br />
<br />
如果说人们对帝国的愿景不一致，那么帝国伟业在实际上也从来不是单一庞大的。从18世纪晚期到19世纪早期，大英帝国开始出现了四种截然不同的形态。第一种形态是自治的殖民地，出现在北美洲、加勒比海地区以及澳大拉西亚。第二种形态出现在印度，它为英国提供了把影响力从波斯湾延伸到中国南海的机会。第三种形态是一些零星的小型地区——其中有些是居住地，如通向印度的小站；有些是贸易转运口岸，比如香港和新加坡，以及东非和西非的一些“近海桥头堡”（还有相对来说未受控制的内陆）。达尔文表示，帝国的第四种形态，是在阿根廷、埃及等地那种非正式的统治。在这些地方，英国通过贸易、投资和巧妙的外交来行使影响力（这种巧妙的外交偶尔也会用得上坚船利炮）。<br />
<br />
What characterised Britain’s empire most was the matchless adaptability of its builders and promoters. As Mr Darwin puts it: “The hallmark of British imperialism was its extraordinary versatility in method, outlook and object.” In particular, the British excelled at recruiting local elites and interest groups as collaborators without whose consent little would have been possible. The whole project could have been doomed by the loss of the American colonies swiftly followed by the “world” war, lasting 25 years, against France (revolutionary and then Napoleonic) and its allies. But by holding on to India, confirming the supremacy of British sea power, and securing a peaceful Europe after Wellington’s victory at Waterloo and the Congress of Vienna, a platform was created for unprecedented expansion. The British world-system then held together until the second world war.<br />
<br />
最能体现英帝国特点的，是其建立者和推动者<font color="Blue">彼此</font>之间那种无与伦比的磨合性。正如达尔文所说：“英帝国主义的特征在于它在方法、观点和目标方面有很大的变通性。”特别值得一提的是，英国人擅长动员当地社会精英和利益集团来与自己合作——如果没有这些人的同意，英帝国寸步难行。英国先是失去了美洲殖民地，之后很快又和法国及其盟国打了一场持续25年的“世界大战”（当时法国先是由革命者控制，后来拿破仑掌权），损失惨重——整个帝国伟业几乎濒临覆灭。但英国紧紧抓住了印度；确定了至高无上的海洋权力；在威灵顿公爵滑铁卢告捷和维也纳会议之后实现了欧洲的和平【注4、5】。借此，英国创立了一个平台来进行史无前例的扩张。其后，英国的世界体系一直维持到第二次世界大战前夕。<br />
<br />
To the unique geopolitical circumstances that British diplomatic genius was able to exploit at this time could be added at least two other critical ingredients. The first was technology. Railways, fast steamships and then the telegraph made it possible to expand, police and govern a vast, sprawling empire in ways that had previously been impossible with a relatively small army and administrative class.<br />
<br />
英国人具有外交天赋，善于利用此时独特的地缘政治形势；除此之外，至少还有两方面的关键因素。其一是技术。铁路、便捷的蒸汽船、还有电报——让英国人<font color="Blue">能够以一些前所未有的方式</font>来扩张、监督并管理一个广阔且不断发展的帝国。而在此之前，由于相对而言军力有限、统治阶层规模不大，<font color="Blue">想要以这些方式来运作帝国是不可能的</font>。<br />
<br />
The second was the emergence of something approaching a guiding ideology of empire: the old buccaneering empire of conquest and commerce never quite disappeared, but the British empire fashioned in the 19th century was believed by many of those involved in the project to be based on “enlightened reform and disinterested trusteeship”. Its purpose was to rescue benighted parts of the world, in the words of the great propagandist, Thomas Macaulay, from “all the evils of despotism and the evils of anarchy”. It was possible to believe that by spreading the blessings of free trade, good governance and technological progress Britain’s empire really was in the interests of all mankind.<br />
<br />
其二就是出现了一种理念，它类似于指导帝国的意识形态：强调征服和贸易、古老的海盗式帝国从未真正消失，但帝国伟业的缔造者认为，19世纪塑造出的大英帝国是以“开明的改革和公正的领土托管”为基础的。用伟大布道者托马斯•麦考利【注6】的话来说，帝国旨在将世界上愚昧落后的地区从“所有专制和混乱的梦魇”中拯救出来。英帝国向世界传播自由贸易、有序治理和技术进步等种种福祉，实际上是在为全人类的利益而服务——这一观点或许真的有几分可信度。<br />
<br />
Of course, the reality was often far darker. The iron fist was always clenched within the velvet glove; protecting indigenous populations from the greed of self-governing white settlers was near-impossible. And the racial solidarity that became a prerequisite of rule after the terrible shock of the great rebellion of 1857 in India is irredeemably ugly to modern eyes. On the other hand, the Britain that had enthusiastically participated in the slave trade in the 1700s threw its naval might into a crusade to banish slavery from the world in the 19th century.<br />
<br />
当然，现实往往要比人们想象的阴暗许多。温情背后，在天鹅绒手套里攥着的永远是一只铁拳。面对白人自治移民的贪婪，保护原住民几乎不可能。印度在1857年爆发了大规模叛乱，在英国引起了强烈的震动。在此之后，种族团结成了统治的先决条件，这在今天看来丑陋得无以复加。但在另一方面，在18世纪还在积极参与奴隶贸易的英国，到了19世纪却发动了海军力量进行废奴运动。<br />
<br />
If a benign geopolitical environment was the bedrock of the 19th-century empire, it was the catalogue of geopolitical disasters of 1940-42 that demolished the British world-system once and for all. Whether the empire could have held for much longer even without those reverses is hard to say. India had become steadily more difficult for Britain to rule and without India, British hegemony in the Middle East, deemed a core national interest until the disaster of Suez in 1956, was increasingly unsustainable. In the context of the cold war between America and Russia, a weakened Britain was no more than a marginal player. However, as Mr Darwin notes, what seems inevitable to us now—the dissolution of empire in a modern world of nation states—did not necessarily appear so at the time or, at least, not immediately. For Britain’s ruling class, including the post-war Labour government, the imperial habit was not easily surrendered.<br />
<br />
如果说有利的地缘政治环境在19世纪为英帝国巩固了基础，那么也正是1940到1942年间的一系列地缘政治灾难彻底瓦解了英国的世界体系。如果没有这种种挫败，英帝国能否维持更长的时间？无法断言。印度对于英国来说日渐难以管制。而直到1956年苏伊士运河危机【注7】为止，英国在中东的霸权一直被认为是核心国家利益——失去印度之后，这一霸权也越来越难以维持。在美苏冷战的背景下，受到削弱的英国只不过是一个边缘角色。然而，达尔文指出：在民族国家组成的现代世界，帝国分崩离析，这在我们今天看来是无可避免的；但在当时却未必如此——至少它不会立刻消亡。对于英国的统治阶级来说（包括战后的工党政府），帝国习性一时还难以放下。<br />
<br />
Bringing together his huge erudition, scrupulous fairness and elegant prose, Mr Darwin has produced a wonderfully stimulating account of something that today seems almost incredible yet was, in historical terms, only yesterday. It is also a much-needed antidote both to the leftish consensus of the past 50 years that Britain’s empire was unrelievedly awful, a catalogue of cruelty, exploitation and racism, and the recent triumphalist revisionism of more conservative historians, such as Niall Ferguson. The British empire was neither good nor bad, but complicated, paradoxical and, above all, of its time.<br />
<br />
达尔文把他的广博学识、审慎公允和清雅文笔糅合到一起，写出了这本趣味盎然的书。它记述的故事在今天看来似乎有点难以置信，然而从历史的角度来说似乎只是发生在昨天。过去50年来，很多人都有一种左派意识，认为英帝国总是很可怖，除了残忍、剥削和种族主义再无其他；而尼尔•弗格森等更为保守的历史学家则秉持一种耀武扬威的近代修正主义。本书也很及时地对这两种思潮进行了矫正。大英帝国无所谓好坏善恶，但它很复杂、很矛盾，而且最重要的是——它属于自己的那个时代。<br />
<font color="Silver"><br />
from the print edition | Books and arts</font><br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>译者注：</strong><br />
<br />
1. 约翰•达尔文为牛津大学教授，当代英国著名的史学研究者。<br />
<br />
2. <a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%8D%E5%88%97%E9%A2%A0%E6%B2%BB%E4%B8%96" target="_blank">不列颠治世</a>（拉丁语：Pax Britannica）是指英国在19至20世纪的兴盛时期。一般认为1815年的滑铁卢战役标志着不列颠治世的开始。<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp; 自1588年击败西班牙无敌舰队后，英国逐渐取代西班牙，成为海上新兴的霸权国家，控制了主要的海上贸易航线，并开始不断扩张海外殖民地。之后，英国相继在英荷战争和七年战争中打败最强劲的对手荷兰和法国，夺取了两国的大片殖民地，确立了海上霸权。<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp; 1815年英国在拿破仑战争中的胜利又进一步巩固了它的国际政治军事强权地位，工业革命更让英国成为无可争辩的经济强权。<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp; 维多利亚时代的大英帝国步入了全盛时期，在1921年，全世界大约4-5亿人——也就是当时全球人口的约四分之一——都是大英帝国的子民，其领土面积则有约3,700万平方公里（它宣称对加拿大北极圈内、澳大利亚内陆和南极洲的土地拥有主权），是世界陆地总面积的24.75%，从英伦三岛蔓延到香港、冈比亚、纽芬兰、加拿大、新西兰、澳大利亚、马来亚、缅甸、印度、乌干达、肯尼亚、南非、尼日利亚、马耳他、新加坡以及无数岛屿。因为地球上的24个时区均有大英帝国的领土，故被称为继西班牙帝国后第二个“日不落帝国”。英国霸权领导下的国际秩序被称为“不列颠治世”。<br />
<br />
3. <a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%8D%E5%88%97%E9%A2%A0%E4%B8%9C%E5%8D%B0%E5%BA%A6%E5%85%AC%E5%8F%B8" target="_blank">英国东印度公司</a>（British East India Company, 简称BEIC）, 又称“可敬的东印度公司”（the Honourable East India Company, 简称HEIC），有时也被称为“约翰公司”（John Company），是一个股份公司。西元1600年12月31日英国女王伊丽莎白一世授予该公司皇家特许状，给予它在印度贸易的特权而组成。实际上这个特许状给予“可敬的东印度公司”于东印度贸易的垄断权21年。随时间的变迁东印度公司从一个商业贸易企业变成印度的实际主宰者。在1858年被解除行政权力为止，它还获得了协助统治和军事职能。<br />
<br />
4. <a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E6%BB%91%E9%93%81%E5%8D%A2%E6%88%98%E5%BD%B9" target="_blank">滑铁卢战役</a>（英文：Battle of Waterloo, 法语: Bataille de Waterloo）是拿破仑战争中的最后一场战役，也是军事史上著名的战役之一。这场战役标志着拿破仑将军的彻底覆灭。<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp; 1815年拿破仑率旧部逃离厄尔巴岛，返回巴黎。英国、普鲁士、奥地利等国集结了70万士兵，分头进攻法国。6月17日，拿破仑击败由布吕歇尔将军率领的普军，指派部下格鲁希元帅消灭逃跑的普军，自己则赶到比利时布鲁塞尔南的滑铁卢村，与由<a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E9%98%BF%E7%91%9F%C2%B7%E9%9F%8B%E7%88%BE%E6%96%AF%E5%88%A9%EF%BC%8C%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E4%BB%A3%E5%A8%81%E9%9D%88%E9%A0%93%E5%85%AC%E7%88%B5" target="_blank">威灵顿公爵</a>率领的英军对峙。可是，格鲁希未能按命令消灭逃跑的普军，反而让普军摆脱了自己的追踪。布吕歇尔摆脱法军的追踪后，花了一个上午重整军队，马不停蹄地奔赴滑铁卢。6月18日，拿破仑率军与英军交战。当天下午，正当两支军队都疲惫不堪时，布吕歇尔率领的普军终于赶到，并猛攻法军的右翼。晚上9时，拿破仑率领的法军败走。<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp; 滑铁卢战役后，联军很快攻占巴黎，拿破仑被放逐到大西洋中的圣赫勒拿岛，六年后死亡。<br />
<br />
5. <a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/zh/%E7%BB%B4%E4%B9%9F%E7%BA%B3%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%AE" target="_blank">维也纳会议</a>是从1814年9月18日到1815年6月9日之间在奥地利维也纳召开的一次欧洲列强外交会议，这次会议是由奥地利政治家梅特涅提议和组织的，其目的在于重划拿破仑战败后的欧洲政治地图。<br />
<br />
6. <a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E6%89%98%E9%A9%AC%E6%96%AF%C2%B7%E5%B7%B4%E5%AE%BE%E9%A1%BF%C2%B7%E9%BA%A6%E8%80%83%E5%88%A9%EF%BC%8C%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E4%BB%A3%E9%BA%A6%E8%80%83%E5%88%A9%E7%94%B7%E7%88%B5" target="_blank">托马斯•巴宾顿•麦考利</a>，第一代麦考利男爵，（Thomas Babington Macaulay, 1st Baron Macaulay，1800年10月25日-1859年12月28日），英国诗人，历史学家，辉格党政治家。他经常发表散文、评论和有关英国历史的文章。他也曾经担任陆军大臣（1839年-1841年）和财政部主计长（1846年-1848年）。<br />
<br />
7.<a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E6%AC%A1%E4%B8%AD%E4%B8%9C%E6%88%98%E4%BA%89" target="_blank">苏伊士运河危机</a>，也被称为苏伊士运河战争、第二次中东战争、西奈战役或卡代什行动，是一次于1956年发生在埃及的国际武装冲突，当时埃及与英国、法国和以色列的军队爆发战争。英、法、以三国的结盟是一种利益的接合：英法两国对苏伊士运河有着贸易利益，而以色列则需要打开运河，以让以色列船只得以通航。到战争结束后，只有以色列获得了巨大的利益。<br />
</td></tr></table>
<div class="attach_nopermission">
<div>
<h3>本帖子中包含更多资源</h3>
<p>您需要 <a href="member.php?mod=logging&amp;action=login" onclick="showWindow('login', this.href);return false;">登录</a> 才可以下载或查看，没有帐号？<a href="member.php?mod=register" title="注册帐号">立即注册</a> 

<a href="http://www.ecocn.org/connect.php?mod=login&op=init&referer=forum.php%3Fmod%3Dviewthread%26tid%3D82787&statfrom=login" target="_top" rel="nofollow"><img src="static/image/common/qq_login.gif" class="vm" /></a>

</p>
</div>
</div>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82787</guid></item><item><title>The new Corn Laws 新时代的《谷物法》</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82753</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_561240">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 豆豆小猴儿 于 2012-9-19 11:56 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
<strong><font color="Red">Food and trade<br />
粮食和贸易</font></strong><br />
<br />
<font size="4"><strong>The new Corn Laws<br />
新时代的《谷物法》</strong></font><br />
<br />
<strong>Trade restrictions to hold down food prices exacerbate the problem they are trying to solve<br />
为降低粮价而采取的贸易限制措施只会适得其反、火上浇油</strong><br />
<br />
THE United States Department of Agriculture confirmed on September 12th what everyone knew: that this year’s American corn (maize) harvest is bad; that three of the biggest wheat exporters, America, Russia and Australia, are suffering from simultaneous droughts; and that the world is experiencing its third food-price spike in five years.<br />
美国农业部于9月12日确认，本年度美国的玉米的收获形势糟糕；此外，世界三大小麦出口国美、俄、澳也正同时遭遇干旱之苦；世界正在经历五年来粮价的第三次暴涨。而在此前，这些消息早已人尽皆知。<br />
<br />
Although the weather is the proximate cause of the price rises, governments are making matters worse. Look at America’s biofuels policy. By ensuring that a third of the country’s maize is turned into ethanol and fed to cars, it has driven up grain prices and made them more volatile by reducing stocks. At the start of this year America scrapped the subsidy for ethanol, and abolished the tariff on imports of the stuff—steps in the right direction. But a certain amount of ethanol still has to be blended with petrol by law. That keeps prices high.<br />
虽然天气因素是导致粮价上涨的直接原因，可政府的所作所为却是火上浇油。看看美国的生物燃料政策就知道了。该政策用于确保美国玉米产量的三分之一都用于制造车燃乙醇，此举不仅抬升了粮价，而且导致粮食存储量下降，从而使粮价动荡不定。今年年初，美国废除了乙醇补贴并停止对其征收进口关税——这些举措算是走对了方向。<font color="#0000ff">然而根据法律规定，汽油必须与一定数量的乙醇勾兑后方可使用。这样做就令粮食价格居高不下。</font><br />
<br />
Bad policies in America are encouraging bad policies elsewhere. Higher prices have spooked importing and exporting countries alike, causing them to turn away from volatile world markets and seek to insulate themselves. Between 2007 and 2011, 33 countries imposed export restrictions on food. Agriculture accounts for less than 10% of world trade, but more than two-thirds of the cost of all border distortions.<br />
美国糟糕的政策正在助使其他地区效仿。上涨的粮价吓到了一些进出口国家，使其避离反复无常的世界市场，转而将自己和国际市场隔绝起来。2007-2011年，33个国家针颁布了措施限制粮食出口。虽然农产品的交易额占世界贸易总量的不到10%，但却占到了边境贸易扭曲总成本的三分之二。<br />
<br />
Export bans are designed to protect consumers from the effects of high prices. From the point of view of a single nation, such a policy might seem to have the desired effect: as world prices spiral upwards, domestic prices are shielded from the full impact. But when many countries do the same thing—as now—so much food disappears from global markets that prices rocket more than they would have done if governments had left well alone. One study calculated that 45% of the huge increase in rice prices in 2006-08 was attributable to trade restrictions. So export bans exaggerate the very thing they seek to defend against.<br />
出口限令旨在保护消费者免受高价带来的影响。从某一国家的角度来讲，这种政策似乎能达到预期效果：由于国际粮价的上升是螺旋式的，国内的粮价就能免于遭受来自国际市场的全面影响。可如今许多国家都这么做，这就使得大量粮食难觅于全球市场，从而导致粮价一飞冲天, <font color="Blue">超过了政府妥为放松监管的结果</font>。据一份研究推算，2006-2008年间，大米价格猛涨，其中45%的价格上涨要归咎于贸易限制措施。所说出口限令恰恰适得其反。<br />
<br />
<strong>Some 2.5 billion reasons to be concerned<br />
理由——与25亿人休戚相关</strong><br />
Higher prices, if sustained, can help poor households in the countryside, many of whom depend on agriculture for their livelihood. But a spike in food prices merely jacks up the cost of living without generating much in the way of income or jobs in the short term; and for the urban poor—who make up an increasing slice of most emerging-country populations—higher food prices are almost entirely bad news. That is why farm-trade restrictions do not cut poverty, but increase it. Scrapping them would pull about 3m people above the poverty line.<br />
农村的许多家庭以农业为生，粮价若持续上涨，这些家庭将从中受益。可是粮价的飞涨仅仅增加了生活成本，却不能在短期内帮助提高收入或是增加就业；在大多数新兴国家的人口构成中，生活在城市中穷人的比重越来越大，对这些人来说，粮价的上涨几乎是个十足的坏消息。这也就解释了为什么说农产品贸易的限制措施会令贫困人口不降反增。将其废除则会让300万人脱贫。<br />
<br />
As if all that were not enough, there is a long-term reason for worrying about government meddling in farming: its rising incidence in China and India. Total state support to Chinese farmers has more than doubled since 2004. China and India are following the ignoble path trodden by Japan, America and Europe in the 1980s: developing an agricultural industry dependent on handouts. It was bad when this happened in the richest parts of the world. Having 2.5 billion people fed by subsidised farming, with its attendant inefficiencies, is worse.<br />
另外，从长远来看，人们也有理由担心政府插手农产品贸易：因为政府的干预正愈发地影响到中印两国。2004年至今中国政府对农民的补贴增加了一倍多。中印两国正在卑劣地重蹈上世纪80年代日、美、欧等国的覆辙：依靠政府补贴来发展农业。这种事情发生在世界上最富有的几个国家就已经够坏了，而让25亿人靠效率低下的农业补贴过日子则更糟。<br />
<br />
Farm protection is like a weed: it grows everywhere and seems impossible to eradicate. This newspaper has been making the case against it since 1843, when we were founded to oppose Britain’s protectionist Corn Laws. Sadly we seem to have made too little progress. At the moment governments are making farming less efficient than it should be. They are increasing poverty. Their policies are otiose, since there are better ways to help the poor, such as direct cash transfers. And they are counterproductive, because they exacerbate the problems they seek to solve.<br />
农业保护如同野草：遍地都是、似乎难以根除。1843年，为了反对英国带有贸易保护性质的《谷物法》，本报应运而生，我们从创刊之日起就一直试图通过晓之以理来反对农业保护。不幸的是，我们的所作所为似乎收效甚微。眼下政府的作为并未让农业发挥其应有效率，反而加剧了贫困。政府的措施如同杯水车薪，因为有更好的办法扶贫，比如直接的现金补助。同时，这些措施也适得其反，因为它们将本要解决的问题激化了。<br />
<br />
This latest spike in food prices will hurt the world’s worst-off. Governments that try to help them by restricting food trade are likely to make things worse still.<br />
最近粮价的上涨将会伤害世界上的穷苦大众。政府想要通过限制粮食交易来帮助他们，到头来很可能让情况一如既往的糟糕。<br />
<br />
【背景阅读】<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;谷物法（Corn Laws）是一道于1815年至1846年强制实施的进口关税，藉以“保护”英国农夫及地主免受来自从生产成本较低廉的外国所进口的谷物的竞争。要注意的是，在英式英语里，“玉米”（corn）这个词语泛指所有谷物，与美式英语专指玉米的意思有所不同。<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;根据David Cody教授的说法：<br />
<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;“谷物法是用来保护英国地主之利益；其手段为，当谷物价格下降到一定程度时，即鼓励出口并限制进口。谷物法最&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; 终在“反谷物法联盟”的军事动乱中被废除了；此联盟在一八三八年时于曼彻斯特成立，宣称谷物法增加了工业生产成本。经过一&nbsp;&nbsp;连串的竞争之后，反谷物法者终于在一八四六年得以遂其心愿，这也象征了英国中产阶级在政治权力中一项重要的胜利。”<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;（中译本） 谷物法使谷米的价格跌至低于某一固定水平之时，透过鼓励出口及限制入口，从而保护英国的地主的利益。<br />
<br />
</td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82753</guid></item><item><title>The new Corn Laws 新谷物法</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82741</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_561082">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 左耳听爱 于 2012-9-18 12:06 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
【导读】：在粮食问题上，政府似乎只会帮倒忙。<br />
<br />
<strong><font size="2"><font color="red">Food and trade<br />
粮食与贸易</font></font><br />
<br />
<font size="4">The new Corn Laws<br />
新谷物法</font><br />
<br />
Trade restrictions to hold down food prices exacerbate the problem they are trying to solve<br />
旨在控制粮价的贸易限制反而加剧了问题的严重性<br />
</strong><br />
<font size="2"><font color="silver">Sep 15th 2012 | from the print edition</font></font> <br />
<img id="aimg_k2kB3" onclick="zoom(this, this.src, 0, 0, 0)" class="zoom" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/original-size/images/print-edition/20120915_LDC083.png" onmouseover="img_onmouseoverfunc(this)" onload="thumbImg(this)" border="0" alt="" /><br />
<br />
THE United States Department of Agriculture confirmed on September 12th what everyone knew: that this year’s American corn (maize) harvest is bad; that three of the biggest wheat exporters, America, Russia and Australia, are suffering from simultaneous droughts; and that the world is experiencing its third food-price spike in five years.<br />
<br />
9月12日，美国农业部证实了几个人人皆知的事实：今年美国的玉米欠收；世界三大小麦出口国，美国、俄罗斯和澳大利亚同时遭遇干旱；五年来，全世界正在遭受第三次粮食价格飙升。<br />
<br />
Although the weather is the proximate cause of the price rises, governments are making matters worse. Look at America’s biofuels policy. By ensuring that a third of the country’s maize is turned into ethanol and fed to cars, it has driven up grain prices and made them more volatile by reducing stocks. At the start of this year America scrapped the subsidy for ethanol, and abolished the tariff on imports of the<font color="red"> stuff</font>—steps in the right direction. But a certain amount of ethanol still has to be blended with petrol by law. That keeps prices high.<br />
<br />
尽管天气是导致粮价上涨的直接原因，但政府却<font color="blue">让事态更加恶化</font>。看看美国的生物<font color="blue">燃料</font>政策就知道了。该政策<font color="blue">规定</font>美国<font color="blue">生产的</font>玉米三分之一<font color="blue">用于提炼</font>乙醇，<font color="blue">作为</font>汽车燃料。<font color="blue">玉米储量减少</font>，导致<font color="blue">谷物</font>价格升高，<font color="blue">也变得</font>更加不稳定。今年初，美国迈出了正确的一步：取消对乙醇汽油的补贴，废除乙醇进口关税。但根据法律，汽油仍旧需要与一定数量的乙醇混合，这使得粮价一直居高不下。<br />
<br />
Bad policies in America are encouraging bad policies elsewhere. Higher prices have spooked importing and exporting countries alike, causing them to turn away from volatile world markets and seek to insulate themselves. Between 2007 and 2011, 33 countries imposed export restrictions on food. Agriculture accounts for less than 10% of world trade, but more than two-thirds of the cost of all<font color="red"> </font><font color="blue">border distortions</font>.<br />
<br />
美国采取的不良政策导致世界其他地区<font color="blue">纷纷效仿</font>。高涨的粮价使粮食进口国和出口国都<font color="blue">恐慌不已</font>，纷纷躲避价格波动的世界市场以求独善其身。2007年至2011年间，有33个国家对粮食<font color="blue">实施了</font>出口限制。<font color="blue">农业</font>贸易在世界贸易中所占的比重不到10%，但在<font color="blue">所有贸易壁垒中，有三分之二以上是有关农业贸易的</font>。<br />
<br />
Export bans are designed to protect consumers from the effects of high prices. From the point of view of a single nation, such a policy might seem to have the desired effect: as world prices spiral upwards, domestic prices are shielded from the full impact. But when many countries do the same thing—as now—so much food disappears from global markets that prices rocket more than they would have done if governments had left well alone. One study calculated that 45% of the huge increase in rice prices in 2006-08 was attributable to trade restrictions. So export bans exaggerate the very thing they seek to defend against.<br />
<br />
出口禁令旨在保护消费者免受高粮价的影响。从单个国家的角度来看，这样的政策似乎能带来预期的效果：世界粮价<font color="blue">急剧</font>上涨，而国内粮价却能免受粮价上涨的全面冲击。但当许多国家都采取这样的做法时（这正是现在出现的情况），大量的粮食从世界市场上消失，导致粮价上涨<font color="blue">速度</font>比政府不干预还要来的快。一份研究报告估计，2006年至2008年，世界上45%的大米价格大幅上涨是由贸易限制造成的。因此，出口禁令<font color="blue">恰恰</font>加重了<font color="blue">人们</font>要解决的问题。<br />
<br />
<strong>Some 2.5 billion reasons to be concerned<br />
<font color="blue">要考虑25亿左右张“嘴”</font><br />
</strong><br />
Higher prices, if sustained, can help poor households in the countryside, many of whom depend on agriculture for their livelihood. But a spike in food prices merely jacks up the cost of living without generating much in the way of income or<font color="blue"> jobs</font> in the short term; and for the urban poor—who make up an increasing slice of most emerging-country populations—higher food prices are almost entirely bad news. That is why farm-trade restrictions do not cut poverty, but increase it. Scrapping them would pull about 3m people above the poverty line.<br />
<br />
如果粮价持续攀升，农村许多以务农为生的贫困家庭就能从中受益。但在短期内，粮价的飙升只会抬高生活成本，并不会给收入带来多大涨幅<font color="blue">或创造多少就业岗位</font>。对于城市里的贫民来说，粮价上涨几乎就是彻头彻尾的坏消息，而这部分人在多数新兴国家所占的比重越来越大。这就是为什么农产品贸易限制不但不会减少贫困，反而会加剧贫困。如果废除贸易限制，世界上300万人就能脱离贫困了。<br />
<br />
As if all that were not enough, there is a long-term reason for worrying about government meddling in farming: its rising incidence in China and India. Total state support to Chinese farmers has more than doubled since 2004. China and India are following the ignoble path trodden by Japan, America and Europe in the 1980s: developing an agricultural industry dependent on <font color="blue">handouts</font>. It was bad when this happened in the richest parts of the world. Having 2.5 billion people fed by subsidised farming, with its attendant inefficiencies, is worse.<br />
<br />
好像这些还不够糟似的，担心政府干涉农业还有一个长期的理由，那就是中国和印度政府越来越来越多地插手农业。自2004年以来，中国政府发给农民的补贴<font color="blue">总额</font>翻了一倍还多。中国和印度正在走20世纪80年代日本、美国和欧洲走过的<font color="blue">糟糕的</font>老路：发展一个依靠<font color="blue">政府补贴</font>的农业。<font color="blue">过去</font>，世界上最富裕的地方<font color="blue">发生这种情况会很糟糕。</font>而<font color="blue">现在</font>，世界上25亿人靠着政府的农业补贴过生活，<font color="blue">同时</font>生产效率还比较低下，则更是糟糕。<br />
<br />
Farm protection is like a weed: it grows everywhere and seems impossible to eradicate. This newspaper has been making the case against it since 1843, when we were founded to oppose Britain’s protectionist Corn Laws. Sadly we seem to have made too little progress. At the moment governments are making farming less efficient than it should be. They are increasing poverty. Their policies are otiose, since there are better ways to help the poor, such as direct cash transfers. And they are counterproductive, because they exacerbate the problems they seek to solve.<br />
<br />
农业保护就像野草一样：它在世界各地疯长，而且似乎无法根除。本<font color="blue">报</font>从1843年以来一直都反对农业保护，而且当初也正是为了反对英国具有保护主义性质的《谷物法》而创立的。遗憾的是，我们似乎<font color="blue">没有取得多大进展</font>。眼下，<font color="blue">各国</font>政府的做法正在使本不该如此的农业变得更加低效，也使贫困日益加重。政府的政策都是多余的，因为还有别的更好的方法可以帮助穷人，如直接<font color="blue">拨款</font>。不仅如此，这些政策还<font color="blue">适得其反</font>，因为它们只会加重原本要解决的问题。<br />
<br />
This latest spike in food prices will hurt the world’s worst-off. Governments that try to help them by restricting food trade are likely to make things worse still.<br />
<br />
最新一轮的粮价飙升将会危及到世界上<font color="blue">最穷的一批人</font>。试图通过限制粮食贸易来帮助穷人的政府很有可能让情况变得更糟。<br />
<br />
<font size="2"><font color="silver">from the print edition | Leaders</font></font> <br />
<br />
参考译法：<br />
Farm protection is like a weed: it grows everywhere and seems impossible to eradicate.<br />
农业保护似野草，四处疯长而几近无法根除。<br />
<br />
<br />
</td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82741</guid></item><item><title>Peddling religion 土耳其的 “伊斯兰自行车&quot;</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82737</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_561060">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 _易雪_ 于 2012-9-18 18:56 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
<strong><font color="DarkOrchid">【导读】</font></strong>土耳其的执政党——正义与发展党（AK党），一直主张温和的伊斯兰教。可现在，有点儿偏了。要想保持竞争力，科技还是比宗教重要些。<br />
<br />
<strong><font color="Red"><font size="2">Turkey and science<br />
土耳其和科学</font></font></strong><br />
<br />
<strong><font size="4">Peddling religion<br />
宗教传播</font></strong><br />
<br />
Why secular academics fret about an “Islamic bicycle”<br />
为什么世俗派学者对“伊斯兰自行车”苦恼不已<br />
<br />
<font color="Silver">Sep 15th 2012 | ISTANBUL | from the print edition <br />
2012.09.15 | 伊斯坦布尔 | 印刷版</font><br />
<br />
“A BICYCLE that is produced with God’s blessings in mind and man’s interests at its fore is an Islamic bicycle.” The pronouncement made at a recent conference in Istanbul by Alparslan Acikgenc, a professor from the Yildiz Technical University, brought nods of approval from his colleagues. “A bicycle that is painted with substances harmful to humans cannot be Islamic,” agreed another professor.<br />
<br />
最近，叶兹科技大学（Yildiz Technical University）的教授阿尔帕斯兰•阿西克兹克（Alparslan Acikgenc），在伊斯坦布尔的一个会议上宣称，“牢记上帝的祝福、将人类的利益摆在首位，这样生产出来的自行车才是伊斯兰教的自行车。”他的同事对此点头称赞。“如果一辆自行车刷的漆对人体有害，那它就不是伊斯兰教的。”另一位教<font color="Blue">授</font>赞许道。<br />
<br />
<img id="aimg_jKj7L" onclick="zoom(this, this.src, 0, 0, 0)" class="zoom" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20120915_EUD001_0.jpg" onmouseover="img_onmouseoverfunc(this)" onload="thumbImg(this)" border="0" alt="" /><br />
<br />
While the exchange elicited a flurry of mirthful commentary, not everyone was amused. Mustafa Akyol, a liberal Muslim writer, called the idea of an Islamic bicycle an “expression of the self-isolating mentality that has stagnated Muslim thought.” Secular academics have long fretted that the mildly Islamist Justice and Development (AK) party, in power since 2002, is promoting Islam ahead of science. They point to the introduction this year of Koran lessons in state-run schools. The emphasis on religious education is part of a controversial overhaul of the national curriculum, which many argue flies in the face of the rigidly secular principles of Kemal Ataturk, Turkey’s founding father. This follows the appointments of overtly pious rectors to various state universities.<br />
<br />
虽然交流会<font color="Blue">引</font>来了一连串欢快的评论，但并不是人人都开心。一位自由派穆斯林作家穆斯塔法•阿克约尔（Mustafa Akyol）称，“伊斯兰自行车”这个概念“表达的是自我孤立，该心态已经让穆斯林的思想停滞不前了。”自2002年起，温和的伊斯兰正义发展党（AK党）开始执政。<font color="Blue">比起科学，它更重视伊斯兰教的发展</font>。很多世俗派学者对此<font color="Blue">一直</font>忧心忡忡。<font color="Blue">他们将矛头指向今年公立学校新增的《古兰经》课</font>。<font color="Blue">对</font>国民教育课程的<font color="Blue">大改革</font>备受争议，宗教教育的重视问题就是其中一部分。说到土耳其国父凯末尔•阿塔图克（Kemal Ataturk）严格的世俗派原则，更是<font color="Blue">众说纷纭</font>。《古兰经》课添加之<font color="Blue">前</font>，AK党又任命那些公开支持伊斯兰教的虔诚领导人为各州立大学的校长。<br />
<br />
“For all their claims of being able to reconcile religion with modernity, Islamic movements in Turkey have signally failed to do so,” argues Ali Alpar, an astrophysicist at Istanbul’s Sabanci University. Mr Alpar is among a group of academics who resigned in protest from the country’s National Academy of Sciences last year after the government announced that it would henceforth be choosing some of its members.<br />
<br />
伊斯坦布尔萨班哲大学（Sabanci University）的天体物理学教授阿里•阿尔帕（Ali Alpar）认为，“尽管他们总声称，自己有能力调节宗教与现代化的矛盾，但土耳其的伊斯兰运动明显没做到。”去年，阿里和一群学者一同从土耳其国家科学院辞职，以表抗议。因为政府宣称，“它以后会筛选一部分科学院成员”<br />
<br />
In the event the government decided to let the country’s top science agency, known as TUBITAK, submit some of the names. Mr Alpar and his friends were unswayed. The agency has been steeped in controversy of its own. This erupted when it allegedly forced the editors of its science magazine to kill a cover story on Charles Darwin in March 2009. The move followed tweaks to TUBITAK’s charter that gave the government a greater say over its affairs. The agency later claimed that it had not censored the piece, blaming the change on editorial wrangles. But Mr Alpar says that an article on Galileo that the agency commissioned him to write was also spiked.<br />
<br />
最终，政府决定让国家的最高科学机构，也就是土耳其科学技术研究理事会（TUBITAK – The Scientific and Technical Research Council of Turkey），提交一些名单。阿尔帕和他的朋友仍不改初衷。该机构自身原本就有矛盾。据说在2009年3月，它强迫自己的科学杂志编辑删除了一篇关于查尔斯•达尔文（Charles Darwin）的封面故事。自此，矛盾爆发了。接着，它对TUBITAK的章程做了些调整，这样一来，政府就更有权干预它的事务了。之后，该机构声称，它当时还没审查那篇文章。把责任推到他人身上：因为编辑争论不休，才会出现那样的变动。但阿尔帕说，该机构委托他写的一篇关于伽利略的文章也被“砍”了。<br />
<br />
Suggestions that AK is steering Turkey towards Islamic rule are overwrought. And as the rest of Europe wrestles with the euro crisis, the Turkish economy continues to grow under AK’s steadying hand. Yet if Turkey is to remain competitive it needs to invest far more in research and development (the Directorate for Religious Affairs, which employs thousands of clerics, was allocated double the amount slated for TUBITAK last year). Alienating the country’s top scientists doesn’t help. “It is time,” says Mr Akyol, “for Muslims to rethink why early Islamic civilisation produced so much of universal value, from algebra to the lute, and why we hardly do that today.”<br />
<br />
AK党政<font color="Blue">正</font>把土耳其导向伊斯兰教统治的方向，<font color="Blue">这一迹象让人过分紧张了</font>。当欧洲其他国家正努力应对欧元危机时，<font color="Blue">土耳其经济在AK党</font><font color="Red">平稳</font><font color="Blue">的领导下</font>，仍在持续增长。<font color="Blue">但是</font>，如果土耳其想维持竞争力，就得在研究和开发上加大投资（土耳其宗教事务局雇佣了上千名牧师。去年，<font color="Blue">土耳其政府</font>拨给<font color="Blue">该局</font>的<font color="Blue">资金</font>是给TUBITAK预计的两倍）。疏远土耳其顶尖科学家<font color="Blue">没什么用</font>。“是时候了，”阿克约尔说，“穆斯林该反思反思，为什么早期伊斯兰文明能创造出那么多具有普世价值的真理，从代数到鲁特琴，应有尽有？为什么我们现在却几乎做不到？”<br />
<br />
<font color="Silver">from the print edition | Europe</font><br />
</td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82737</guid></item><item><title>Investment banking Dream turns to nightmare 投行 美梦成魇</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82735</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_561057">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 坏娃娃 于 2012-9-20 18:26 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
<strong><font size="2"><font color="red">Investment banking<br />
投资银行</font><br />
</font></strong><br />
<font size="4"><strong>Dream turns to nightmare<br />
美梦成魇</strong></font><br />
<br />
<strong>Investment banking once delivered juicy profits. No longer<br />
曾赚得盆满钵满的投资银行，如今风光不再</strong><br />
<br />
<font size="2"><font color="silver">Sep 15th 2012 | from the print edition </font></font><br />
 <font color="black">&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; <img id="aimg_VQvri" onclick="zoom(this, this.src, 0, 0, 0)" class="zoom" width="595" height="335" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20120915_FNP001_0.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></font><br />
<br />
&quot;THE best countercyclical indicator of the health of capital markets is when investment banks cut staff,” says a senior banker at a large American investment bank. “We always cut <font color="blue">just</font> before the cycle turns.” But what if the cycle doesn’t turn? <font color="red"><font color="blue">An industry</font> </font>that once seemed to offer banks the opportunity to earn juicy returns and expand internationally is now in retreat almost everywhere.<br />
“银行裁员的时机是资本市场健康状况最灵敏的反周期指示器，我们总是在市场周期<font color="blue">刚</font>变化之前裁员。”美国一家大型投资银行的高级银行家如是说道。但是，如果市场周期不变化怎么办？<font color="blue">投资银行业</font>曾给银行奉上了赚取丰厚回报和海外扩张的良机，但现在几乎在全线收缩。<br />
<br />
Some of this withdrawal has been going on since the crisis—the fees paid to banks for trading in capital markets as well as for advising on takeovers and sales of shares and bonds have been falling for a few years now. But lately retreat has turned to rout. Early this month Nomura, which had made a gutsy bet on expansion when it bought the European and Asian businesses of Lehman Brothers in 2008, in effect pulled the plug on its global investment-banking business. Peers express little surprise. “Nomura was dead before it started,” says the boss of one large bank. “It was a totally ill-conceived foreign expansion.”<br />
经济危机伊始，银行业便开始萎缩。银行收取的费用呈降低之势已有几年有余，这些费用包括资本市场交易费以及兼收并购咨询费和股票债券交易费。可是，银行业最近的收缩蜕变成了溃败。本月初，在2008年收购了雷曼兄弟在欧洲和亚洲业务部门之后大胆扩张的野村集团，实际上已削减了其全球投资银行业务。同行对此略感惊奇，一位大型银行的总裁更是说道“野村出师未捷身死，应归罪于根本就考虑不周的海外扩张计划。”<br />
<br />
Yet other banks are pulling back hard, too. Deutsche Bank, Germany’s banking champion, plans deep cuts to its investment bank, a part of the business responsible for much of its growth. Barclays is said to be considering slimming its investment bank by as much as a fifth, reversing a decade-long expansion of a business that contributes more than half of total profit. Both Barclays and Deutsche are lowering their targets for<font color="blue"> returns on equity</font>, in Deutsche’s case to just 12% after tax, well down on the 25% pre-tax target it once aimed for.<br />
现在，其他银行也在努力收缩业务范围。德国银行业领头羊德意志银行计划大幅裁减为其增长立下汗马功劳的投资银行业务。据称，巴克莱银行正考虑缩减多达1/5的投行业务规模，撤销扩张长达十年的业务，而该业务带来的利润占总利润的一半以上。巴克莱和德行均降低了各自的<font color="blue">净资产回报率</font>目标，德行降低至税后12%，远低于之前税前25%的目标。<br />
<br />
There are two main reasons for the sharp falls in profitability at investment banks everywhere. The first is that their clients are simply doing a lot less business with them. Income from trading bonds, currencies and commodities (an area of activity known in the industry as FICC) has fallen as<font color="blue"> slowing economies and turmoil in Europe</font> have discouraged institutional investors from trading and companies from buying one another or issuing shares. Equity issuance worldwide dropped by about 30% in the first seven months of this year<font color="blue"> from a year earlier</font>; in debt markets, bond issuance has fallen by about 8%, according to analysts at Mediobanca, an Italian bank. Number-crunchers at Deutsche Bank reckon that revenue from investment banking around the world will total some $240 billion this year, down by almost a third from 2009 (see chart).<br />
投行盈利能力整体剧烈下滑有两个主要原因。首先是客户与银行之间业务量大量减少。由于<font color="blue">世界经济减速及欧洲经济的乱局</font>挫伤了机构投资者和企业的信心，他们不再愿意进行股票交易或是发行新股，所以债券、货币和大宗商品交易（这些都是行业中固定收益部门的业务）给银行带来的收入锐减。据意大利地中海银行分析师称，<font color="blue">今年前七个月较去年同一时期世界范围内新发股票量减少了约30%</font>，债券市场中新发债券量下降了8%。德行的会计师认为：今年全世界投行所带来的收入总计约2,400亿美元，较2009年下降约1/3（如图表所示）。<br />
<img id="aimg_zs248" onclick="zoom(this, this.src, 0, 0, 0)" class="zoom" width="290" height="281" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20120915_FNC069.png" border="0" alt="" /><br />
 <br />
The second reason is that regulations on capital and liquidity are starting to bite.<font color="blue"> These are reducing returns earned by banks as well as forcing them to shrink their balance-sheets and cut back on trading</font>. Many banks are also starting to position themselves for proposed rules that are not yet in force, such as America’s Volcker rule, which aims to stop banks trading for their own account, and regulations that will shove over-the-counter derivatives, which command fat margins, onto clearing-houses and exchanges.<br />
第二个原因是对资本和流动性的监管措施正开始发威。<font color="blue">这些监管措施迫使银行缩减资产负债表规模并交易量，同时也减少了经营回报。</font>一些银行也开始主动接受已提上日程但并未实施的监管条例，诸如致力于阻止银行自营交易的沃尔克法则以及其他监管条例，限制在结算所和交易所使用带来丰厚利润的场外衍生工具。<br />
<br />
Not everyone is gloomy: J.P. Morgan reportedly says<font color="red"> <font color="blue">investment banking</font></font> has never been stronger. But most other banks seem to have lost their mojo. The most visible consequence of this is in headcount. London’s financial industry will have lost about 100,000 jobs by the end of this year from a peak of 354,000 in 2007, according to CEBR, an economics consultancy. New York’s financial comptroller reckons Wall Street employs almost 20,000 fewer people than before the crisis.<br />
并非所有的人都满面愁云：据称，摩根大通认为<font color="blue">自己的投行业务</font>从没有像现在这么强大。但是大多数其他银行似乎好运不再，而最直观的后果便是雇员数量。据英国经济与商业研究中心（Centre for Economics and Business Research, CEBR）数据显示：伦敦金融业到今年年底为止将会减少100,000个职位，而在2007年雇员人数达到了顶峰354，000人。<br />
<br />
Slashing variable costs is only half the story, however. The industry is reshaping itself in other ways, too. First, there is the decline of stand-alone investment banks, and the concomitant resurgence of universal banks, which combine investment banking with the simpler commercial-and retail-banking sort. Diversified, deposit-taking universal banks can maintain higher credit ratings and can borrow more cheaply than specialist investment banks such as Morgan Stanley or Goldman Sachs. As credit has become scarce, moreover, <font color="blue">universal banks have been able to demand a larger share of lucrative investment-banking business from their clients in return for offering loans.</font><br />
尽管如此，大幅削减投资银行业务仅是权宜之计。而银行业也在向其他的方向转型。首先，自成体系的投行正在没落，而综合性银行相应地正在复苏；综合性银行将投资银行业务和较为简单的商业及零售银行业务整合。多元化业务，吸收储蓄的综合银行能够维系较高的信用评级，而且借贷成本较像摩根斯坦利和高盛这样的专业化投资银行低。随着信贷正变得稀缺，<font color="blue">而且综合性银行已经有能力从客户那里获得更多能够带来丰厚利润的投行业务, 作为提供贷款的回报。</font><br />
<br />
In response, investment banks such as Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley are trying to expand into corporate lending, private banking and <font color="blue">retail stockbroking</font>. This week Morgan Stanley reached a deal to buy out Citigroup’s 49% stake in their Smith Barney retail-broking joint venture.<br />
作为回应，高盛和摩根斯坦利这样的投行正在试着向企业贷款、私人银行和股票零售业务领域扩张。本周，摩根斯坦利就收购花旗银行合资公司史密斯•巴尼的<font color="blue">个人客户股票经纪业务</font>49%的股权达成协议。<br />
<br />
The second shift in the investment-banking landscape is a<font color="blue"> hollowing-out</font> of the midsized banks as the very biggest in the industry grab a greater share of trading revenues. This is partly because the titans can afford the best trading systems, but also because a bank with a large share of trading has the liquidity that further increases its attractiveness as a trading counterparty. Analysts at Deutsche Bank reckon that the five leading banks in FICC won 40% of the market’s revenue in 2011, up from 36% in 2007. Smaller banks that once aspired to be global are expanding in markets closer to home instead.<br />
投资银行业务场景的另一转变是：由于行业巨头攫取了交易收入中的大部分份额，中等规模银行面临<font color="blue">业务空心化</font>的处境。产生这一局面部分是因为银行巨头们能够提供最好的交易体系，部分是因为占据大部分交易份额的银行具有足够的流动性，能进一步增加其作为交易方的吸引力。德行分析师认为五大银行固定收益部门占据的市场收入份额从2007年的36%上升到了2011年的40%。而曾备受鼓舞想要全球化业务的小型银行正向离本土不远的市场扩张。<br />
<br />
The more open question is whether the industry’s geographical centre of gravity will also move, away from London and towards Wall Street and Asia. London’s natural advantages of time zone, law and language are not easily bettered. But Asian and American banks have big deposit bases to call on to finance expansion; European banks generally do not. And London’s reputation has been sullied by recent regulatory failures over issues such as the rigging of LIBOR interest rates, as well as the <font color="blue">political backlash against investment banking that arose as a result</font>. “London hit Ctrl-Alt-Delete in terms of wanting to be a centre of global finance,” says the boss of one large universal bank. “Singapore and New York will be the new hubs of global finance and <font color="blue">you can’t open enough coal mines…to make up for that</font>.”<br />
更具争议性的问题是：银行业的地理中心是否也会转移，由伦敦转向华尔街和亚洲。伦敦具有时区，法律和语言等天然优势，而这些优势并不容易被超越。但是亚洲和美国的银行有巨大的存款基础来支持金融扩张，这一点是欧洲银行通常所不具有的。而且伦敦的声誉受到了严重打击，这都是拜最近监管不力（比如伦敦同业银行拆放利率操纵丑闻）和<font color="blue">由此引发的政治压力</font>所赐。一位综合性银行的高管说道：“伦敦想要成为全球金融中心的野心已经终止。新加坡和纽约将会成为新的全球金融枢纽，<font color="blue">即便是开再多煤矿，也无法弥补伦敦丧失金融中心地位的趋势。</font><font color="red"><br />
<br />
</font>参考：<br />
Volcker Rule 沃克尔规则：沃克尔规则是多德-弗兰克法案中的一则条款，由美联储前主席沃克尔在担任奥巴马经济复苏顾问委员会主席期间提出，主要倡导银行业限制利用自有资金买卖股票、债券、货币、商品及其衍生品等自营业务，防止过度投机，降低银行业系统性风险。<br />
<br />
Libor (London Interbank Offered Rate)<br />
伦敦同业拆放利率，是一个英国银行同业之间的短期资金借贷款的成本，由英国银行家协会（British Banker's Association）按其选定的一批银行，于伦敦货币市场报出的银行同业拆借利率，计算出平均指标利率。<br />
<br />
FICC （Fix Income, Commodity and Currency）<br />
主要是做债券、外汇及大宗商品等有稳定未来现金流产品的部门，或通过组合构造出较稳定现金流的金融产品。</td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82735</guid></item><item><title>An atheist’s guide 无神论者指南</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82691</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_560723">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 左耳听爱 于 2012-9-17 16:26 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
【导读】：到底是上帝创造人，还是人创造上帝？这本讲述基督教起源的新书为我们揭开其中的奥秘……<br />
<strong><br />
<font size="2"><font color="red">The origins of Christianity<br />
基督教起源</font></font><br />
<br />
<font size="4">An atheist’s guide<br />
无神论者指南</font><br />
<br />
A new book argues that St Paul was the key to Christianity’s success<br />
一本新书称圣保罗是基督教成功的关键</strong><br />
<br />
<font size="2"><font color="silver">Sep 15th 2012 | from the print edition</font></font> <br />
<img id="aimg_A6qD6" onclick="zoom(this, this.src, 0, 0, 0)" class="zoom" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20120915_BKP003_0.jpg" onmouseover="img_onmouseoverfunc(this)" onload="thumbImg(this)" border="0" alt="" /><br />
<font size="2">St Paul seeking guidance<br />
圣保罗寻求指<font color="blue">引</font></font><br />
<br />
<strong>And Man Created God: Kings, Cults, and Conquests at the Time of Jesus.</strong> By Selina O’Grady. <i>Atlantic; 393 pages; £20. To be published in America in March by St Martin’s Press; $26.99.</i> Buy from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1843546965/theeconomists-20" target="_blank">Amazon.com</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1843546965/theeconomists-20" target="_blank">Amazon.co.uk</a><br />
<br />
<strong>《<font color="blue">于是</font>，人类创造了上帝：耶稣时代的君主、宗教信仰和征服》</strong>，塞琳娜•奥格莱迪著。<i>大西洋出版社出版，全书393页，售价20英镑。美国地区由圣马丁出版社出版，将于2013年3月上市，售价26.99美元。</i><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1843546965/theeconomists-20" target="_blank">Amazon.com</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1843546965/theeconomists-20" target="_blank">Amazon.co.uk</a>有售。<br />
<br />
THE rulers of ancient Rome were ruthlessly pragmatic in matters of religion. When a tribe was subdued and its lands added to the imperial realm, Rome would appropriate the subject-people’s gods and add them to an ever-growing pantheon of exotic divinities. When Augustus asserted supreme political power, he also claimed divine status; the cities of the empire were encouraged to compete with one another in the fervour of their emperor-worship.<br />
<br />
古罗马时期的统治者在面对宗教问题时，<font color="blue">理性务实、</font>冷酷无情。当一个部落被罗马征服，其领土被纳入罗马帝国版图后，被征服地区人们所信仰的<font color="blue">诸神</font>也会被一并吸收<font color="blue">并添加</font>到罗马那充满异国神祇且日益壮大的万神殿①中。奥古斯都②宣称他拥有至高无上的政治权利，同时也宣<font color="blue">告</font>他拥有<font color="blue">如神一般</font>的地位。在统治者的鼓励下，罗马<font color="blue">帝国各城市</font>的居民竞相比较谁对君主的崇拜更加狂热。<br />
<br />
In her sweeping account of relations between faith and power at the dawn of the Christian era, Selina O’Grady presents the political uses of pagan religion, set amid all the luxury and decadence of Roman life, with great relish and descriptive power. She goes on to examine the interplay of authority and faith in many other parts of the world, particularly in Persia, India and China. <font color="blue">The result is an enjoyable, informative romp </font>through the subject of comparative religion.<br />
<br />
在书中，塞琳娜•奥格莱迪详尽地描述了基督教时代<font color="blue">刚刚开始时</font>信仰与权力的关系。她将异教置于罗马帝国那奢靡腐败的生活中，用充满乐趣的文字和强有力的描述手法展现了异教的政治用途。接着她又关注了权力与信仰在世界其他地区的相互作用，特别是波斯、印度和中国这几个地区。<font color="blue">结果她写出的这本书妙趣横生、开卷有益</font>，贯穿了比较宗教学这一主题。<br />
<br />
But Ms O’Grady, a British broadcaster and writer, has a more ambitious purpose. By looking at many different forms of theocracy and Caesaropapism, she hopes to create a context that renders comprehensible the emergence of Jesus of Nazareth as a preacher in villages in Galilee, the wildfire spread of Christianity, and its adoption as the official religion by the Roman empire. In other words, she is seeking a straightforward secular explanation for the historical phenomenon that Christianity itself<font color="red"> </font><font color="blue">ascribes to</font> the work of the Holy Spirit.<br />
<br />
但是奥格莱迪女士（<font color="blue">她是</font>英国的广播员<font color="blue">兼</font>作家）<font color="blue">的雄心壮志不止于此</font>。她希望在观察许多不同形式的神权政体或政教合一的政体后，能写出一篇文章，使人们充分理解，拿撒勒③的耶稣最初出现时是加利利④地区村庄的一名传教士，之后基督教如野火一般传播开来，最终被罗马帝国定为国教。换句话说，她在寻找一种<font color="blue">通俗易懂</font>的说法，来解释基督教本身就<font color="blue">称得上</font>是圣灵的工作⑤这一历史现象。<br />
<br />
She thus enters an arena into which biblical scholars began crowding half a century ago: how, <font color="red">if at all</font>, does the “historical Jesus” relate to the Christ of faith and dogma? With<font color="blue"> accomplished</font> journalistic flair, she posits answers with far greater confidence than any academic writer, <font color="blue">choking on</font> footnotes, could muster.<br />
<br />
由此她<font color="blue">登上</font>了半个世纪前圣经学者们<font color="blue">就开始</font>蜂拥聚集的舞台：“历史上的耶稣”到底是如何与宗教和教义上的救世主联系起来的（如果真的能联系起来的话）？塞琳娜•奥格莱迪作为一个<font color="blue">颇具</font>资质的新闻工作者，自信地给出了她的答案——这种自信远<font color="blue">非</font>任何<font color="blue">绞尽脑汁加脚注</font>的学术<font color="blue">作家所能企及</font>。<br />
<br />
To the scholarly secular enquirer, certainty about the historical Jesus is elusive. The written evidence is thin to non-existent, and the import of the Dead Sea Scrolls, one of the few sources for the period that is mainly in a Semitic language, is hotly contested. But Ms O’Grady’s ideas are very clear. Jesus, for her, was one of many wandering preachers and miracle-workers who made no particular claim to be divine but did articulate a form of Jewish nationalism. (Why, one might object, did he urge followers to “render unto Caesar what is Caesar’s?”) The “Son of God”, in whose name Roman and Byzantine emperors ruled, was in Ms O’Grady’s view constructed by Paul, who fashioned Christianity into a religion that was both universalist (appealing, as Islam does, to the whole of humanity) and politically quietist, and therefore ideal for an empire.<br />
<br />
对于博学的<font color="blue">世俗调查者</font>来说，耶稣的<font color="blue">历史身份是很难确定的</font>。有关这方面的书面证据<font color="blue">极</font>少，几乎<font color="blue">可以算是</font>不存在，《死海古卷》⑥是有关那个时代的少数资料中的其中一份，但古卷主要是用闪族语写成的，因此它的<font color="blue">内容</font>也存在很大争议。但奥格莱迪女士表达的观点十分清晰。对她而言，耶稣就是漫游的传教士和圣迹创造者中的其中一个，<font color="blue">他</font>并不明确称自己是神圣的，但<font color="blue">他</font>的确清楚表达了一种犹太民族主义。（有人可能会提出反问：为什么耶稣要力劝他的追随者“凯撒的物当归给凯撒”呢？）罗马帝国和拜占庭帝国借“耶稣基督”的名义统治臣民，而在奥格莱迪女士看来，这一名义正是保罗⑦建立起来的。保罗将基督教塑造成一种宣扬普救说（像伊斯兰教一样，能吸引全人类）和政治寂静主义⑧的宗教，这样，这种宗教对帝国来说就很理想了。<br />
<br />
The author makes some good points. Imperial peace, both in ancient Rome and in other eras, was in a paradoxical way a cause of social and cultural dislocation. It made commerce and travel possible, allowing intercourse between separate ethnic and religious groups. Her argument that universalist religion is useful to an empire is sound though not original; work by a British scholar, Garth Fowden, on monotheism in late antiquity should have been included in her bibliography.<br />
<br />
本书作者提出了不少颇有见地的观点。在古代罗马以及其他年代，帝国的和平都是导致社会和文化错位的原因，<font color="blue">这使它的存在显得十分矛盾</font>。它使贸易和旅行<font color="blue">成为</font>可能，<font color="blue">让</font>来自不同民族不同宗教信仰的人们互相交流。<font color="blue">作者认为</font>宣扬普救说的宗教对帝国有利。这一观点虽然不是她原创的，但却十分<font color="blue">合理</font>。此书的参考文献中应该会提到这一观点的提出者，即英国学者Garth Fowden有关古代晚期一神论的一篇文章。<br />
<br />
Ms O’Grady <font color="blue">observes</font> that Paul was, in a sense, solving a private problem when he devised a religion for the whole of humanity—the identity problem of a devout and zealous Jew who had a Greek education and was a Roman citizen. Three centuries later, Rome’s masters found that Paul’s answer to his own dilemmas corresponded precisely to the empire’s ideological needs.<br />
<br />
奥格莱迪女士<font color="blue">评论道</font>，从某种意义上讲，对上帝虔诚又热心的保罗在为全人类带来基督教的同时其实是在解决一个私人问题，即一个<font color="blue">犹太人的</font>自我定位的问题。保罗是一个罗马公民，但他接受的却是希腊教育。三个世纪过去了，罗马的统治者们发现保罗为他自己的困境所找到的答案正好符合了帝国统治在思想意识形态上的需要。<br />
<br />
Her argument rises to a crescendo in a final chapter about how “Paul created Christ”; or how the apostle devised a serviceable form of world-religion based on his <font color="blue">mystical intimations</font><font color="red"> </font>of a divine figure whom he had “met” only in visions. Both ends of her argument—that Paul responded creatively to his personal dilemmas, and that belief in one God held the late Roman empire together—are convincing enough; but in her attempts to trace what happened in the first 300 years of Christian history, many causal links are missing. Even were the reader persuaded to allow that enduring jail, whippings and shipwrecks was Paul’s own approach to identity politics, it is still hard to understand how he persuaded so many others to follow suit. Whatever the answer, it surely takes more than a 30-page chapter to set it out.<br />
<br />
作者在最后一章中通过论述“保罗是如何创造基督的”将全书推向高潮。或者说，作者论述的是<font color="blue">这</font>个信徒是如何在<font color="blue">一位</font>圣人给他的<font color="blue">神谕</font>的基础上，创造出一个能为人所用的世界宗教，而这个圣人他只在自己的想象中“见到”过。作者<font color="blue">得出的两个结论</font>都足以让人信服：第一，保罗积极地面对他自身所处的困境；第二，罗马帝国正是因为有了对上帝信仰才得以<font color="blue">维系</font>。但是，作者在追溯基督教发展的前300年历史、试图弄清这一阶段发生了什么时忽略了许多因果联系。即使作者说服读者相信保罗在忍耐监禁、鞭打和海难的过程中达到了对自身政治身份的认同，读者仍旧很难理解保罗是如何让其他<font color="blue">许多</font>人做到像他一样。无论答案是什么，要想解释清楚这一问题，<font color="blue">一个短短30页的章节肯定是不够的</font>。<br />
<br />
<font size="2"><font color="silver">from the print edition | Books and arts <br />
</font></font><br />
<strong>背景参考：</strong><br />
①<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/47548.htm" target="_blank">万神殿</a><br />
②<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/25812.htm#4" target="_blank">奥古斯都</a><br />
③<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/247442.htm#3" target="_blank">拿撒勒</a><br />
④<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/750769.htm#3" target="_blank">加利利</a><br />
⑤<a href="http://www.jdtjy.com/html/jiaomushuji/shenxueziliao/shenglinglun/htm/01.html" target="_blank">圣灵的工作</a><br />
⑥<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/79694.htm" target="_blank">死海古卷</a><br />
⑦<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/210407.htm#sub6261522" target="_blank">保罗</a><br />
⑧<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/2677173.htm" target="_blank">寂静主义</a><br />
<br />
<strong>参考译法</strong>：<br />
When a tribe was subdued and its lands added to the imperial realm, Rome would appropriate the subject-people’s gods and add them to an ever-growing pantheon of exotic divinities. <br />
在（罗马）征服了一个部落，并将其领土划入到罗马皇家版图后，罗马进一步将属民信奉的圣灵一并纳入到日益壮大的万圣殿（万神殿）的众位异教诸神中。<br />
<br />
In her sweeping account of relations between faith and power at the dawn of the Christian era, Selina O’Grady presents the political uses of pagan religion, set amid all the luxury and decadence of Roman life, with great relish and descriptive power.<br />
书中，作者Selina O’Grady在详尽的描写基督教时代兴起开端，信仰和权力关系的字里行间，采用大篇幅的能调起人胃口的字眼，强有力的描述，为读者展现了在罗马纸醉金迷，堕落颓废的生活中，异教是如何操控政治的。<br />
<br />
</td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82691</guid></item><item><title>Coming out 出柜</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82682</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_560675">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 盛夏浅 于 2012-9-22 23:58 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkOrange">【导读】</font>当下，中国对同性恋仍然存在偏见和歧视。把同性恋列入“性偏离”范畴和“预防同性恋”的错误信息将使“恐同”情绪更为严重。传播正确科学的同性恋知识显得尤为重要。多一些尊重理解和包容，为同性恋者创造更宽松多元的社会环境。不让青少年同性恋者在校园中遭受歧视，让他们的青春能多一丝阳光。<br />
<br />
<font size="2"><font color="Red"><strong>Homosexuality<br />
同性恋</strong></font></font><br />
<br />
<font size="4"><font color="Blue"><strong>Coming out<br />
出柜</strong></font></font><br />
<br />
<strong>More gay teenagers are gaining acceptance by their parents<br />
越来越多的青少年同性恋正在被父母所接受 </strong><br />
<br />
<font color="Silver"><font size="2"><i>Sep 15th 2012 | SHANGHAI | from the print edition</i> </font></font><br />
<br />
<font size="3">HOMOSEXUALITY was declassified as a mental illness in China a decade ago, but prejudice remains deep. So when an editor at the government education department in the city of Hangzhou was compiling a pamphlet recently to help parents guide their children through puberty, she included a warning about “deviant” behaviour.<br />
<br />
尽管早在十年前，<font color="Blue">同性恋在中国就不再归类为精神疾病，</font>但到现在，偏见仍蒂固根深。比如最近，杭州市政府教育局的一位主编在编写宣传手册《青春期请家长同行》时，就警告父母注意“性偏离”行为。<br />
<br />
What she may not have expected was an irate open letter in response from a group of。 mothers of gay children. Eighteen mothers, from all over China, affiliated with Parents, Families and Friends of Lesbians and Gays, an NGO known as PFLAG China, signed the letter. It called for the book to be withdrawn.<br />
<br />
让这位编者没有料到的是，这惹怒了草根组织“同性恋亲友会（英语简称PFLAG China）”的“妈妈团”。该组织来自大江南北的18位同性恋母亲联名发布公开信要求当局召回此书。<br />
<br />
“We’re extremely angry about this,” one of the signatories says who asked only to be identified by her internet name: Romantic Mum from Hebei. “Understanding and accepting gay people starts with education,” she continues. “But if kids continue to get this kind of education, the prejudice will remain.”<br />
<br />
“我们对此感到十分气愤，”河北省一位只愿透露网名“浪漫妈妈”的签名者表示，“理解和接受同性恋应从教育开始，”她继续说道，“要是儿童继续接受这种不正确的教育，对同性恋的偏见将继续存在”。<br />
<br />
The mother says her own “unsuitable education” meant that she was devastated when her son came out to her at the age of 15: “I kept asking myself what I had done wrong in bringing him up.” But last year, after joining some online discussion groups, she accepted that her son was not going to change. Now she helps run PFLAG’s hotline, which offers advice to parents of gay children.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br />
<br />
该母亲认为是她自己教育不当，以至于当她儿子15岁向她出柜时，她几近崩溃：“我一遍遍问自己，养育他的这些年我到底做错了什么”。但在去年加入在线聊天群后，她接受了儿子性向没办法改变的这一事实。现在她正在帮助接听亲友会热线，<font color="Blue">向同性恋的父母提供咨询服务。<br />
</font><br />
PFLAG’s director, Hu Zhijun, says that ten years ago very few children came out to their parents. Now, with more information available online, a new generation of gay people are more confident. “They’re more likely to tell their parents and classmates,” he says.<br />
<br />
亲友会执行主任胡志军表示，10年前，很少有孩子向父母坦白。但现在不同了，有了能获得更多信息的网络渠道，新一代同性恋人群也变得更加有信心。“<font color="Blue">他们向父母和同学出柜的可能性更大了，”</font>他说道。<br />
<br />
The government editor’s response was encouraging too: she invited the volunteers for a chat, apologised for not knowing much about gay people, and said there will be changes in the next edition of the book.<br />
<br />
这位<font color="Blue">杭州市政府的主编</font>也做出了同样令人鼓舞的回应：邀请志愿者聊天，为自己不太了解同性恋人群而道歉，并表示，在该书第二版中，将对涉及到同性恋的内容进行修改。<br />
<br />
But there is much more to do, says Romantic Mum. Her parents and close friends have been surprisingly accepting of her son’s homosexuality, but the boy’s father has not, and now barely talks to him. And although Mr Hu and his group have recently given talks in universities, schools are more resistant. He estimates that perhaps 10% of gay people in China now tell their parents. Most of the rest still feel they must get married to satisfy their families.<br />
<br />
“浪漫妈妈”说，要做的还有很多。<font color="Blue">意外的是，她父母和好友都接受了她儿子是同性恋。</font>但儿子父亲却还没有，到现在也几乎不和儿子讲话。<font color="Blue">尽管最近，由胡带领的同性恋亲友会在大学举办巡回讲座, 但是中小学校还很抵制同性恋讲座进校园的活动。</font>他估计，中国现在可能只有10%的 同性恋者向父母出柜，其余大部分则仍然认为他们必须结婚来给家人一个交代。</font></td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82682</guid></item><item><title>Five out of ten 得分不及格</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82660</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_560584">
<i class="pstatus"> 本帖最后由 盛夏浅 于 2012-9-16 18:50 编辑 </i><br />
<br />
<strong><font size="2"><font color="Red">Apple’s new smartphone<br />
苹果的新智能手机</font></font></strong><br />
<br />
<strong><font size="4"><font color="Black">Five out of ten<br />
得分不及格</font></font></strong><br />
<br />
The iPhone 5 is hardly a great leap forward<br />
iphone 5 未实现质的飞跃<br />
<br />
<i><font color="Silver"><font size="2">Sep 15th 2012 | SAN FRANCISCO | from the print edition<br />
</font></font></i> <br />
<img id="aimg_7wP7p" onclick="zoom(this, this.src, 0, 0, 0)" class="zoom" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20120915_WBP010_0.jpg" onmouseover="img_onmouseoverfunc(this)" onload="thumbImg(this)" border="0" alt="" /><br />
<font color="Red">The smartest phone in the room?<br />
iphone5，发布会上最智能的手机？<br />
</font> <br />
<br />
<font size="3">SOME hilarious videos doing the rounds on the internet show people pretending to take photos with invisible iPhones and hold conversations on them. These spoofs are meant to poke fun at Apple and its legion of fans. But the very notion that the firm could produce a see-through phone also highlights how closely its brand has become associated with revolutionary innovations. What a pity, then, that the iPhone 5, which was unveiled on September 12th, fails to live up to that hard-won reputation.<br />
<br />
网上有一段“隐形iphone”的恶搞视频十分流行，在该视频里人们煞有介事地用手掌拍照片打电话。这些滑稽模仿都是在拿苹果公司和果粉开涮。但苹果公司有能力生产透明手机的这一观念也突出了苹果就是“革命性创新”的代名词。但遗憾的是，9月12日发布的iphone 5 却辜负了它来之不易的美誉。<br />
<br />
The device is thinner than its predecessors, has a bigger screen and boasts connectivity to superfast 4G wireless networks. But it now competes against impressive offerings from the likes of South Korea’s Samsung and other rivals, who are constantly churning out snazzier superthin handsets of their own with stunning displays. They are unlikely to lose much sleep because of the incremental changes made to the iPhone 5.<br />
<br />
比前几代iphone相比，Iphone 5 更薄，屏幕也更大，并支持4G极速无线网络。但现在，韩国三星等公司也能生产出同样出色的产品，这意味着苹果公司的iphone 5 所面临的竞争巨大。这些公司不断<font color="Blue">推出</font>一系列显示效果极佳的更炫超薄手机。<font color="Blue">所以对于Iphone5的渐进式改进，他们并不怎么感到焦虑。<br />
</font><br />
This is a high-stakes game for Apple, whose phone business still accounts for more than half of its revenues. These are not about to plummet: hordes of folk still want to get their hands on smartphones. IHS, a research firm, reckons that next year global shipments of smartphones will exceed those of non-smart ones for the first time. But the iPhone is facing much stiffer competition from handsets using Google’s popular Android operating system. According to IDC, another research firm, Android’s share of smartphone sales rose from 24% in 2010 to 66% in the first half of this year; Apple’s grew by four percentage points, to 20%, over the same period.<br />
<br />
这是一场高风险的博弈。因为手机业务仍为苹果公司收入打下了大半壁江山。虽然手机销量不会骤减，因为很多人仍想入手智能机。调研公司IHS表示，明年全球智能机出货量将首次超过非智能机。但谷歌安卓系统的手机<font color="Blue">也广受喜爱，可以说，iphone所面临的是一个强手如云的市场。</font>另一家调研公司IDC表示，从2010年到今年上半年，智能手机销量中安卓手机份额从24%上升到了66%。而在此期间，苹果只上涨了4个百分点，达到20%。<br />
<br />
The company still has an important advantage over its rivals in the form of its huge “ecosystem” of digital apps, 700,000 of which are now available in its online store, and cloud-based services such as iTunes, which is getting a revamp. And that advantage will be reinforced by the firm’s new mobile operating system, iOS 6, which will power the iPhone 5 and a smaller iPad tablet computer Apple is expected to launch later this year. The system includes a new digital-mapping app developed by Apple and a feature that allows users to store things such as digitised aircraft boarding passes and movie tickets. These and other offerings can be combined to make mobile commerce more seamless. “The ability to tie digital stuff into the real world is becoming much more important for users,” says Ian Fogg, an analyst at IHS.<br />
<br />
不可否认，比起竞争对手，苹果公司仍具有很大优势，比如其网上商店拥有70万数字应用的生态系统，还有正在升级的iTunes等云服务。此外，苹果公司还将发布新的移动操作系统iOS 6来支持今年晚些时候发售的iphone 5 和 Mini Pad. 这会使苹果的优势更为突出。iOS 6 中包括苹果新开发的数字地图应用和储存数字登机牌和电影票等的应用。所有的新应用可以更加无缝地整合到移动商务中。HIS分析师Ian Frogg表示，“对用户来说，把数字化融入到现实生活的能力正变得越来越为重要。”<br />
<br />
Indeed it is. But other firms such as Amazon, which is rumoured to have a smartphone in the works, and Google are busy beefing up their ecosystems of software and hardware too. So Apple will have to work harder to stay ahead of the pack or risk seeing some of its profits vanish like those imaginary phones.<br />
<br />
数字化也的确变得越来越重要。<font color="Blue">但其他公司如亚马逊和谷歌也不容小觑，他们都在积极强化自己的硬件和软件“生态系统”，而且据传言亚马逊也在为发布自己品牌的智能手机做准备。</font>因此，想继续保持领先，苹果公司实在需要加把劲儿了，否则就可能面临风险，眼睁睁看着自己的部分利润像视频中的“隐形iphone”一样不翼而飞。<br />
</font></td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82660</guid></item><item><title>Air travel 空中旅行</title><link>http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82657</link><description><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td class="t_f" id="postmessage_560572">
<font size="2"><font color="Red"><strong>Air travel 空中旅行</strong></font></font><br />
<br />
<strong><font size="4">Preparing for take-off 起飞准备&nbsp; &nbsp;<br />
A cheaper, cleaner way for the long taxi to the runway一种更便宜更清洁的飞机跑道滑行方式</font></strong><br />
<br />
Sep 15th 2012 <i>from the print edition</i><font color="Silver"></font><br />
<br />
ENGINES on airliners are highly efficient when they are in flight, but not when operating on the ground. When a plane is taxiing under its own power, the engines burn vast amounts of fuel. A Boeing 747 can consume a tonne of fuel and emit several tonnes of carbon dioxide during an average 17-minute taxi to take-off. And when the aircraft lands there is likely to be another long drive to the passenger gate. Which is why there are various methods being developed for aircraft to use other means of propulsion while moving around an airport.<br />
<br />
飞机上的发动机在飞行过程中效率是很高的，但是在地面上的时候却不是这样。飞机依靠自身动力滑行时，发动机燃烧掉大量的燃料。一架波音747起飞一般需要滑行17分钟，要消耗1吨燃料并且释放出几吨二氧化碳。飞机着陆时，也要滑行很长一段才能到达<font color="Red">乘客出口</font>。这就是为什么要研究不同的方法让飞机在机场运行时使用其他的动力方式。<br />
<br />
Towing aircraft with a tug, similar to how they are pushed back from the gate, is one way. But constantly pulling on the front landing gear can lead to mechanical problems. Many pilots would also prefer to be in control of the driving once their aircraft is on the taxiway.<br />
用飞机拖拉车牵引就是一种办法，类似于发动机的推力。但是经常拉拽前起落架可能会导致机械故障。许多驾驶员在飞机滑行的时候也喜欢自己来控制操作。<br />
<br />
One method that addresses both concerns is a semi-robotic tug called TaxiBot, developed by Israel Aerospace Industries (IAI). Instead of using a tow bar attached to the aircraft’s nose wheel, TaxiBot employs a mechanism which automatically scoops the wheel up into a rotating turret.<br />
<br />
能同时解决这两方面问题的一种方法是一种半机器人化的牵引车：牵引机器人。它是由以色列航空工业公司研发的。牵引机器人运用一种机械装置可以自动托起飞机前起落架与旋转塔台连接。<br />
<br />
The TaxiBot also avoids having any complicated links to connect to the cockpit, yet still gives the pilots driving control. It does this by accelerating to the speed set for the taxiway, using its inbuilt GPS map system. The pilots then use their usual controls to steer with the nose wheel (which in turn steers the TaxiBot) and to brake with the main landing gear. A safety driver remains in the TaxiBot, and he also drives the vehicle to and from the aircraft.<br />
<br />
牵引机器人连接驾驶舱也不需任何复杂的元件，驾驶员却可以控制操作。牵引机器人利用内置的GPS地图系统给跑道速度控制装置加速即可。驾驶员用通常的控制器完成头部机轮的控制（头部机轮反过来控制牵引机器人）和主起落架的制动。牵引机器人里也有一位司机，负责将其开到地方和驶离。<br />
<br />
With the high price of aviation fuel—a tonne can cost more than $1,000—the savings at a busy airport could be large. At some airports the passenger gates can be several miles from the runway. All told, the world’s airlines spend $7 billion-8 billion a year taxiing between passenger gates and the runway, says Yehoshua Eldar, who is in charge of business development at IAI. The TaxiBot, though, uses just 20-30 litres of fuel for a typical trip. It also reduces the risk of debris being ingested by the engines and causing damage. Germany’s Lufthansa will trial the system at Frankfurt Airport from May 2013.<br />
<br />
航空燃料的价格很高，一吨价值1000多美元，一个业务繁忙的机场因此可以节省大批资金。一些机场登机门和跑道之间相距好几英里。以色列航空工业公司业务发展部负责人约书亚.埃尔达说：全世界的机场每年在跑道和登机门之间滑行上的花费合计达70-80亿美元。可是牵引机器人一次标准的旅行却仅用20-30升燃料。而且牵引机器人还可以降低飞机发动机吸入碎片造成破坏的风险。德国汉莎航空公司将从2013年5月开始试行这个系统。<br />
<br />
In the future some airliners may be driven to and from the runway with electric power. The German Aerospace Centre has tested this idea in an aircraft using a fuel cell to power two electric motors built into the hub of an aircraft nose wheel. The centre reckons that up to 19% of current airport emissions could be saved using such a system. And it would also please the neighbours: there would be hardly any noise during taxiing.<br />
<br />
将来飞机可能会利用电力在跑道上滑行。德国宇航中心已经就此进行了实验：在一架飞机上用燃料电池给装在飞机头部机轮<font color="Red">轮毂</font>里的两台电动机提供动力。该中心测算出应用这一系统最多可以减少19%的飞机排放物。而且机场周围的邻居也会高兴：飞机滑行过程中几乎没有任何噪音。</td></tr></table>
</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ecocn.org/forum.php?mod=viewthread&tid=82657</guid></item></channel></rss>
